In order to be successful, you have to
要想获得成功，你必须
be able to communicate your ideas, who
能够清晰地表达你的想法、
you are, and your point of view. And so,
你的为人以及你的观点。 因此，
I use three steps in every communication
我在每一次沟通中都会使用三个步骤，这些步骤既
that can be used for getting a
可以用于
promotion, laying people off. It could
升职，也可以用于裁员。 它可以
be used to persuading your significant
用来说服你的
other, "Where are you going to go to
另一半：“你今晚打算去哪里
dinner that night?" And it allowed me to
吃饭？” 它让我从
go from being in a room where I couldn't
一个无法
have a conversation with people and
与人交谈、
crippled with anxiety and fear to
焦虑恐惧到
co-founding two nine-figure businesses,
共同创立两家九位数企业、
helping over 15,000 business owners
帮助超过 15,000 名企业主
scale their organizations, as well as
扩大组织规模，以及
helping people unpack the strategies
帮助人们了解
that the top 1% of people use to gain
顶尖 1% 的人用来获得
wealth and success that are different
财富和成功的策略，这些策略与
than 99% of people who can't create the
99% 无法创造
wealth that they've always wanted. Like
他们一直想要的财富的人的策略截然不同。
they prioritize being respected over
他们似乎更看重被人尊重，而不是被人
being liked.
喜欢。
&gt;&gt; And where else do people go wrong here?
人们在这里还有哪些地方会出错？
&gt;&gt; Well, ultimately this comes down to the
归根结底，这取决于一个
character of the person. If the person
人的品格。 如果一个人
isn't somebody who wants to win, who
没有必胜的决心，
doesn't sacrifice, you cannot get to
没有做出牺牲的勇气，你就无法达到
where you want to go. Now, of course,
你想要的目标。 当然，
you could try to hack success, but if
你也可以尝试走捷径获得成功，但如果
you did it by putting in the effort, you
你是通过努力获得的，你
don't have this anxiety that it's all
就不会有那种担心一切会崩塌的焦虑，
going to come crashing down because you
因为你
know that you could redo it and it's
知道你可以重来，而且永远不会让你
never burnoutinducing. That's a
精疲力竭。 这是
misconception about hard work. You're
对努力工作的误解。 你
not a candle. You can't burn out.
不是蜡烛。 你不会精疲力竭。
&gt;&gt; What about passive income? Because the
那么被动收入呢？ 因为
idea that you can make income and do is
能够赚钱并从事自己喜欢的事情的想法，实在
unbelievably compelling.
太有吸引力了。   在
&gt;&gt; Well, before you have a million dollars,
你拥有一百万美元之前，千万别
don't even think about passive income.
考虑被动收入。
Instead, use your calendar as a
相反，你应该将日历作为
important with the goals that you have
你
every single day.
每天设定的目标和重要事项的体现。
&gt;&gt; But if someone at home isn't quite clear
但如果家里有人不太清楚
on their goals, what should they be
自己的目标，他们应该怎么
doing?
做呢？
&gt;&gt; I have a three-step methodology for goal
我有一个三步目标
setting that I have rolled out to
设定方法，我已经将其推广到
thousands of people and it's called PPF
成千上万的人身上，它被称为 PPF，
and it's transformed my life. So, the
它改变了我的生活。 首先，
&gt;&gt; I see messages all the time in the
我经常在
comment section that some of you didn't
评论区看到一些留言，说你们有些人没有
realize you didn't subscribe. So, if you
意识到自己没有订阅。 所以，如果您
could do me a favor and double check if
能帮我个忙，再次确认一下
you're a subscriber to this channel,
您是否是本频道的订阅者，我
that would be tremendously appreciated.
将万分感激。
It's the simple, it's the free thing
这是件简单又免费的事情，
that anybody that watches this show
任何经常观看本节目的人都
frequently can do to help us here to
可以做，以帮助我们
keep everything going in this show in
保持本节目目前的良好发展
the trajectory it's on. So, please do
势头。 所以，请您
double check if you've subscribed and uh
再次确认是否已订阅，
thank you so much because in a strange
非常感谢，因为从某种意义上说，
way you are you're part of our history
您是我们历史的一部分，
and you're on this journey with us and I
您与我们一起踏上了这段旅程，我
appreciate you for that. So, yeah, thank
为此感谢您。 是的，谢谢
you
你，
Natalie. For my viewers that have just
娜塔莉。 对于刚刚点开
clicked on this conversation, what is
这个对话的观众，
the reason that you think it's important
您认为
for them to stay and listen to what
他们留下来听
we're going to talk about today and all
我们今天要讨论的内容，以及
of the things that you've spent your
您毕生致力于
career understanding? If you are
理解的所有事情，为什么如此重要？ 如果你是一个
working hard and putting in the effort
努力工作、投入时间
and the energy, but you don't actually
和精力，但却没有积累
have wealth to show for it, this
财富的人，那么这次
conversation is important because wealth
谈话就很重要，因为财富
should come from hard work on the right
应该来自于对正确问题的辛勤工作
set of problems. And so you have to ask
。 所以你必须问问
yourself the question, what problems do
自己，
I work on every single day? And whether
我每天都在处理哪些问题？ 无论
you're a team member in an organization,
你是组织中的团队成员、
organization, a business owner in an
组织中的领导者还是组织中的企业主
organization, you should be able to
，你都应该能够
objectively point at my work here
客观地指出我在这里的工作
generated this result. And so if I'm
产生了这一结果。 所以，如果我
upset with this result, meaning I
对这个结果感到不满，意味着我
haven't made the wealth, I haven't
没有赚到我想要的财富，没有
created the income that I want, it would
创造我想要的收入，那么
make sense that where you're spending
你把时间花在哪里
your time and the problems that you're
以及你正在
solving are not tied to your actual goal
解决的问题与你增加财富的实际目标无关，这很正常
of increasing your wealth. And when it
。 就
comes to wealth, I do think that we are
财富而言，我认为我们正处于
in a wealth crisis across the globe. I
全球性的财富危机之中。 我
think that there is so much confusion
认为人们
and misunderstanding about financial
对金融
literacy and what's actually happening
知识，以及人们实际在
with who is making money, how they're
赚钱、如何
making money, what they're spending
赚钱、把
their time on. And so this conversation
时间花在什么地方等方面，存在着很多困惑和误解。 因此，
I'm very much looking forward to
我非常期待通过这次对话，
unpacking what are the strategies that
深入探讨那
people use the 1% for their time, for
1% 的人在时间、
their investments, for their skills, for
投资、技能和
their mindset that are just different
思维方式上所采用的策略，这些策略与
than 99% of people who can't seem to get
99% 的人截然不同，而这些人似乎无法取得
ahead and create the wealth that they've
成功，也无法创造他们
always wanted.
一直渴望的财富。
&gt;&gt; And so as you sit here now, what is your
那么，你现在坐在这里，你的目的是什么呢
business? What's the scale of the
？ 这家企业的规模有多大
business? And uh what does it do? Yeah,
？ 那它有什么作用呢？ 是的，
over the last six years, I co-founded
在过去的六年里，我联合创办了
two businesses that are both nine
两家公司，如今这两家公司的年收入都达到了九
figures today. One is a management
位数。 一家是管理
consulting investment firm. It's called
咨询投资公司。 它名为
Cardone Ventures, and we help small
Cardone Ventures，我们帮助小型
business owners grow and scale their
企业主发展壮大他们的
organizations. So, I work with business
企业。 因此，我
owners on a daily basis who will be
每天都与
doing $3 million in annual revenue. They
年收入达 300 万美元的企业主打交道。 他们
want to know, how do I become one of the
想知道，如何才能成为
fewer that is able to have a $5 million
少数能够拥有年营业额 500 万美元
a year business or a $10 million a year
或 1000 万美元的
business? because they really realized
企业的人之一？ 因为他们真正意识到，
that $3 million a year doesn't actually
每年300万美元并不能真正
create financial security. And that
带来财务保障。 这家
business was started in 2019. And then
公司成立于 2019 年。然后，
our second business, 10X Health, we
我们的第二家公司 10X Health，我们
purchased a health business back in 2023
于 2023 年收购了一家健康公司，
and today is helping people all over the
如今它正在帮助世界各地的人们，
world and it's a nine figure business.
并且是一家年收入达九位数的公司。
&gt;&gt; So you're on that first business. How
所以你现在正在处理第一笔生意。
many business owners have you worked
你曾与多少位企业主合作过
with?
？
&gt;&gt; Total business owners that have come
参加过我们项目的企业主总数
through our programs would be over
将超过
15,000. What what are the range of
15,000 人。
things you're helping them with?
你帮助他们的具体工作范围是什么？
&gt;&gt; Great question. So, there's education.
问得好。 所以，还有教育。   是的
Yeah. There's consulting, there's
。 有咨询，有
services, and there's investing. So,
服务，还有投资。 所以，你可以把
think of us like the McKenzie for small
我们看作是小型
businesses. We reverse engineer their
企业的麦肯齐律师事务所。 我们会反向分析他们
current market, what they're doing, what
目前的市场、他们的业务、
their products, services, offerings are,
产品、服务和产品组合，
and we give back to them either in the
然后以
form of actual services where we will do
实际服务的形式回馈他们，例如为他们做市场
their marketing for them, we will
营销、为他们
recruit people for them, we will do
招聘人员、
their bookkeeping for them. But then we
为他们做记账。 但我们的
our business where we train business
业务中还有一个庞大的活动部分，我们会培训企业
owners on how to hire, how to recruit
主如何招聘员工，如何自行招募人才
themselves. So they don't need to hire
。 所以他们不需要雇佣
us to do it. I actually prefer it when
我们来做这件事。 我其实更希望
people don't hire us to do this because
人们不要雇佣我们来做这件事，因为
I think it's so important for business
我认为对于企业
owners and the leaders inside those
主和
teams to actually get the competence in
团队领导者来说，掌握
that skill. So if you use Yeah. have
这项技能非常重要。 所以如果你使用是的。 有
hiring or their books. If if business
招聘人员或他们的书籍。 如果企业
owners don't understand how to read a
主不了解如何阅读
P&amp;L and the importance of a balance
损益表和资产负债
sheet, they're always going to abdicate
表的重要性，他们总是会把
that work to somebody else. And at some
这项工作推给别人。 但到了某个
point, that is not going to work for
时候，这种方法对
them any longer because I don't actually
他们来说就行不通了，因为我其实并不
know what that skill is. So, I'm
知道他们掌握的是什么技能。 所以，我
trusting that Steven can come into my
相信史蒂文能够加入我的
business. Steven seems great. I know him
公司。 史蒂文看起来很棒。 我
from church. I'm just going to let
在教堂认识他。 我就让
Stephen do this. But, I don't know that
斯蒂芬来做这件事吧。 但是，我不知道
Steven only knows how to do this to a $3
史蒂文是否只知道如何对付一家价值 300
million business. And I need it to be a
万美元的企业。 我需要它成为一家价值
$10 million business. there's no
1000万美元的企业。 目前还没有任何
education system that exists for
教育体系可以
business owners to help them identify
帮助企业主认识到这一点
that today.
。
&gt;&gt; So it was a 2019 you started this
所以你是在2019年创办了这家
business.
公司。
&gt;&gt; So if I jumped back to 2019,
那么，如果我回到 2019 年，
be successful in business that you know
你现在所知道的、在商业上取得成功的原则，与
now that you wouldn't have known then?
当时所不知道的，有哪些根本性的区别呢？   有
Like what are the glaring principles? I
哪些显而易见的原则？ 我
often think that like the further you go
常常觉得，就像你在
down any path,
任何一条路上走得越远，就越能
&gt;&gt; it becomes more and more clear what the
清楚地看到
like fundamental rules of the game are.
游戏的基本规则是什么。
And at the very beginning, those are
而这一切，在最初都只是
just hypotheses. So, what are like the
假设而已。 那么，在
that you've interfaced with that are
你接触过的15000名
business owners um makes some of them
企业主中，你了解到哪些基本因素导致一些人
successful and the others unsuccessful?
成功，而另一些人失败？
&gt;&gt; I ultimately think that this comes down
我最终认为，这归根结底取决于
doing the business. Because if you look
经营者的品格。 因为如果你看看那些
at people that you can partner with in
可以和你一起做生意的人
business, it is incredibly challenging
，你会发现要
to make something truly successful. Even
取得真正的成功是非常具有挑战性的。 即使
if it's the best business model in the
它是世界上最好的商业模式
world, you figured out marketing, you
，你解决了营销问题，
figured out operations, you can scale
解决了运营问题，你也能扩大规模
it. If the person is a piece of [__] and
。 如果一个人是个人渣，
if the person is not somebody who is
没有
ethical and is somebody who's compliant
道德底线，只会顺从，不想
and isn't somebody who wants to win, to
赢，在
me those three things go hand in hand
我看来，这三件事是密不可分的，
because it to me it doesn't matter what
因为对我来说，
the business model is. You could give me
商业模式是什么都无关紧要。 你可以给我
a roofing business, you can give me an
一家屋顶公司，你可以给我一家
HVAC business, you can give me a
暖通空调公司，你可以给我一家健康公司，你可以给我
wellness company, a marketing agency.
一家营销机构。
The principles that I thought to be
我曾经认为
true, many of them have held true over
正确的许多原则，在
the last six years since 2019. Many of
过去六年（自 2019 年以来）中仍然适用。
them are still very applicable around
其中许多原则在
standard practices for accounting and
会计标准做法和
how you recruit people. Certain tips and
人员招聘方面仍然非常适用。 某些技巧和
tools help with different platforms that
工具可以帮助你在不同的平台上
you can use for these things, but for
完成这些事情，但
the most part, those things actually
总的来说，这些事情本身并
haven't changed. But what I've learned
没有改变。 但过去六年里，我痛苦地认识到，
everything is about the people that you
一切都取决于你与哪些人
do business with and the partners that
做生意、
you choose and the people that you allow
你选择哪些合作伙伴以及你允许哪些人
in your inner circle. And so that is the
进入你的核心圈子。 所以，
case for your own business, but that's
对于您自己的企业来说是这样，
also the case for the businesses that we
对于我们
help. And I can watch the most
帮助的企业来说也是如此。 我亲眼见证了一位
incredible business owner come into our
杰出的企业主加入我们的
organization. She's wanting to win.
组织。 她想赢。
She's excited about what the future can
她对未来充满期待
look like. She's going to take all of
。 她会把所有
the notes and actually go home and
笔记都记下来，然后回家认真
implement those things. But if she has
实践。 但如果她
somebody in her life, say it's a spouse,
生活中有人，比如配偶、
say it's a kid, worse yet it's an
孩子，或者更糟糕的是，
employee that she's paying to help her.
她雇佣的员工来帮助她。
Like that's the irony. You pay people to
这就是讽刺之处。 你花钱请人来
help you and yet when they're actually
帮助你，但当他们真正成为
on your team, they do things that
你的团队成员时，他们却做出一些
detract from your ability to achieve
削弱你实现
your goals and to reach your potential.
目标和发挥潜力的事情。
That's where I find doesn't matter what
我觉得
the business model is, doesn't matter.
商业模式是什么并不重要。
You can give all of the books, all of
你可以把所有的书籍、所有的
the training, the full playbook to
培训、完整的策略手册都给
somebody, they're going to fail because
一个人，他还是会失败，因为
either they aren't that person or
要么他不是那种人，要么
they've surrounded themselves inside
他身边的
their business with people who will just
人只会
be stops to them and continually stop
阻碍他，不断阻止
their ability to grow and to reach for
他成长和追求
more, reducing that person's confidence
更高的目标，降低他
in themselves and their business stays
对自己和事业的信心，使他的事业
stuck.
停滞不前。
&gt;&gt; If people are the most important thing
如果人才是企业
for long-term success and for business,
长期成功和发展的关键，那么
what are you looking for in people? What
你希望从人才身上看到什么？
makes someone an A player in your view?
你认为什么样的人才算得上A级球员？
And how do you how do you filter them
那你如何筛选
out?
掉它们呢？
Because a lot of people go off their
因为很多人都凭感觉行事，
vibes and if I've learned anything over
而过去十年我最大的感悟
the last 10 years is that we're all
就是，我们都
riddled with our own biases and
深受自身偏见和
insecurities. So we end up aiming in a
不安全感的影响。 所以最终我们会朝着
certain direction whether that's for
某个方向努力，无论结果是
better or for worse.
好是坏。
&gt;&gt; So what's your process of finding
那么，你们寻找优秀人才的流程是什么
exceptional people?
？
&gt;&gt; I use a three-step interview process. So
我采用三步面试流程。 所以
the three steps for me is first a
对我来说，这三个步骤首先是
cultural interview. I want to understand
文化面试。 我更想了解的是，
more so than me trying to get into the
我是否能够胜任这项
technicalities of can they do the work.
工作，而不是纠结于技术细节。
Are they aligned with our organization?
他们与我们组织的理念一致吗？
Are they goal oriented? The best
他们是否目标明确？ 在聘用公司内部
question that you can ask somebody
人员之前，你能问的最好的问题是：
what are their five-year goals and
他们的五年目标是什么？这样才能
actually get a real answer. I don't
真正得到一个真实的答案。 我并
really care what skills and experiences
不在意你拥有什么技能和经验
you have. If you don't have goals,
。 如果你没有目标，
you're I'm not hiring you. You're not
我就不录用你。 你
allowed to be inside this environment
不被允许待在这种环境下，
because it's demoralizing for every
因为这会打击
other person who is here to help achieve
其他来这里帮助
their goals. the organization's goals
他人实现目标的人的士气。 组织的目标，
and hopefully the goals of the end
以及最终
customer, client, patient for whatever
客户、顾客、患者（无论何种
type of business. So that first
类型的企业）的目标。 因此，第一次
interview really being the cultural
面试作为文化
grounding point is of the utmost
基础面试至关重要，
importance and then I move straight into
之后我会直接进入
a technical interview where I want to
技术面试，让
get the person as close to the work as
应聘者
possible. So if you're going to be a
尽可能地了解实际工作内容。 所以，如果你想成为一名
salesperson, I want to see you make a a
销售人员，我想看看你如何进行
sales call. I'm going to give you a list
销售电话。 我会给你一份包含
of 50 people to call. I want to listen
50 个联系人的名单，你需要给他们打电话。 我想听
to you call those people. If you are a
你给那些人打电话。 如果你是
graphic designer in our organization, we
我们公司的平面设计师，我们
do not do briefs. We are not the type of
不接受设计简报。 我们不是那种会
people that are going to say you get all
说给你所有
of this time to be able to think through
时间去思考
this whole process and this whole
整个过程和整个
journey and we're going to give you two
旅程，然后给你
weeks to do this. For us, we are
两周时间来完成这件事的人。 对我们来说，我们需要
turnurning content constantly because
不断地制作内容，因为
that's the world that we live in for the
我们身处的世界就是如此，
amount of ads that need to be created,
需要制作大量的广告和
presentation decks. It can't take a
演示文稿。 不能花太
bunch of time. And so if the person when
长时间。 因此，如果
I do a case study interview and I have
我进行案例研究访谈，并让受访者
them actually make a presentation in
在
front of me says that they need two days
我面前进行演示，而受访者却说他们需要两天时间
to think about this and they can't
来思考，并且无法
a graphic for an ad. They don't know how
为广告制作任何形式的演示文稿或图表，那么他们就会这样做。 他们不知道如何
to use Adobe or Canva or whatever the
使用Adobe、Canva或其他类似的
platform is, I I can't really hire the
平台，我不能雇用这样的
person because I know that they don't
人，因为我知道他们不
have that skill. And then the final one
具备这项技能。 最后一部分
is a core values interview. And for me,
是核心价值观面试。 对我而言，
our team's ability to demonstrate ahead
团队成员能否在
of time, ahead of joining the
加入
organization that they actually
公司之前就展现出他们真正
understand and are in alignment with our
理解并认同我们的
core values is essential.
核心价值观，这一点至关重要。
&gt;&gt; How do you test someone's core values?
如何检验一个人的核心价值观？
&gt;&gt; Well, I asked them to give me times
我请他们举例说明
where they have exemplified the core
他们是如何体现
values that we have and they present it
我们核心价值观的，然后让他们
to our leadership team. For the first
向我们的领导团队汇报。
100 team members at Cardone Ventures, I
在 Cardone Ventures 成立后的前 100 名团队成员中，我认真
listen to every single core values
聆听了每一位成员的核心价值观
presentation. the person can't
演讲。 这个人无法
demonstrate and actually say, "Oh, I was
证明并真正地说：“哦，我
able to generate x amount of leads and
能够产生 x 个潜在客户，并
convert them at y percentage." They
以 y% 的转化率转化他们。” 他们
probably don't know what they're talking
可能根本不知道自己在说什么，
about and they're gonna have a really
而且他们
hard time in the environment. And I do
在这种环境下会过得很艰难。 而且我确实认为
believe that this is the business
这是企业
owner's responsibility. You have to own
主的责任。 你必须对
your culture and your environment. And
自己的文化和环境负责。
if you don't and just think that anybody
如果你不这样做，只是认为任何
that can come in is going to actually
能进来的人都会按照
live by what you want to create, you're
你想要创造的方式生活，你
going to be very quickly mistaken
很快就会犯错，
because they're going to create their
因为他们会
own environment inside yours and then
在你的环境里创造他们自己的环境，然后
you've lost control. You talked about
你就失去了控制。 你曾说过，在与
you're meeting people. What is what is
人会面时，设定目标至关重要。
your framework for goal setting? If
你设定目标的框架是什么？ 如果
someone at home isn't quite clear on
家里有人不太清楚
their goals, what what should they be
自己的目标，他们应
doing?
该做什么？
&gt;&gt; I have a three-step methodology for goal
我有一个三步目标
setting that I have rolled out to
设定方法，我已经将其推广到
thousands of people. And this three-step
成千上万的人身上。 这个三步
framework has really transformed my life
框架真的改变了我的生活，
because it allows me to create buckets
因为它让我能够
for goals. And the process is called
为目标创建分类。 这个过程被称为
personal goals, professional goals, and
个人目标、职业目标和
financial goals. And after having over a
财务目标。 在
personally where I've interviewed team
我亲自与团队
members and business owners and team
成员、企业主以及
members of business owners about their
企业主的团队成员就他们的
goals, what I can say is I've never
目标进行过一千多次对话之后，我可以肯定地说，我从未
found a goal that is outside of those
发现过一个目标超出这
three buckets. But the challenge many
三个范畴。 但很多
people run into is on New Year's Eve,
人遇到的挑战是，在新年夜，
they start to list out all of the lovely
他们开始列出所有
things that they would like to
他们想要
accomplish and who they want to be. And
完成的美好事情以及他们想要成为的人。 于是，
conversation. Instead of really
对话就变得非常深奥晦涩了。 与其真正从
prioritizing personally, what does
个人角度出发考虑优先事项，不如思考一下
success look like? Professionally, what
成功究竟是什么样的？ 从职业角度来看，
does success look like? Financially,
成功是什么样的？ 从财务角度来看，
what does success look like? And what
成功是什么样的？ 那么，
would those targets be in one year from
一年后
now, 3 years from now, and 5 years from
、三年后、五年后，这些目标会是什么
now? Because those three buckets become
？ 因为在短期内，这三个方面很
easy to think about in the short term.
容易被考虑。
One year for most people, super
对大多数人来说，一年就够了，非常
straightforward. They're like, "Oh, I'd
简单。 他们会说：“哦，我
like to make an additional $10,000.
想再赚1万美元。
Maybe I'd like a promotion here." Three
也许我想在这里升职。”
years starts to get a little bit more
三年这个时间跨度开始变得有些
nebulous. And after having over a
模糊了。 经过
thousand of these conversations, 5 years
上千次这样的对话，5 年的时间里，
for most people they have a hard time
大多数人很难再进行这样的
thinking with. But the one constant is
思考。 但有一点可以肯定，
in 5 years from now, guess what? We're
5年后，你猜会发生什么？ 我们
going to be 5 years older. I am 32 years
就要老五岁了。 我
old today. In 5 years from now, for
今天32岁了。 五年后，
certain, I will be 37 years old. And so,
我肯定就37岁了。 那么，
who is Natalie at 37?
37岁的娜塔莉究竟是怎样一个人呢？
&gt;&gt; Who is she?
她是谁？
&gt;&gt; She's a [__] badass.
她真是个狠角色。
Natalie is in control of her
娜塔莉能够掌控自己的
environment. Natalie is able to
环境。 娜塔莉能够
make a lot of financial investments that
进行很多
I'm not in the position financially to
我目前经济状况不允许我
make today because I want to be able to
进行的投资，因为我想能够随意
write a million dollar check to charity
给慈善机构开一张一百万美元的支票，
just because I can. I'd ideally like
仅仅因为我有能力这样做。 我理想情况下希望
that check to be 10 or $50 million. And
支票金额是 1000 万或 5000 万美元。
when you say PPF, personal,
说到 PPF，指的是个人、
professional, financial,
职业、财务，
&gt;&gt; is there any specific way that I should
我应该如何具体地
write this down? Is it just do I just
书写呢？ 我是否只需要
think about in 5 years from now, what
思考一下五年后
are my personal, professional, and
我的个人目标、职业目标和
financial goals? And then I write that
财务目标是什么？ 然后，比如，我会把它写
down on a piece of paper, for example.
在纸上。
&gt;&gt; Great question. Ideally, personal is at
问得好。 理想情况下，个人预算应该
the top,
放在首位，
&gt;&gt; okay,
可以，然后分别设置
&gt;&gt; with a bucket for one year, three year,
一年、三年
and 5year.
和五年的预算。
&gt;&gt; Then the next is professional, one year,
接下来是职业阶段，一年、
three year, five year. Financial one
三年、五年。 财务
year, three year, five year.
年度：一年、三年、五年。
&gt;&gt; And you know, you use the word badass.
而且你知道，你还会用“牛逼”这个词。
&gt;&gt; Uhhuh.
嗯哼。
What is the mindset of a badass? Like,
一个狠角色的心态是怎样的？
have you always been like this?
你一直都是这样吗？
&gt;&gt; I always wanted this, but today I am
我一直都想要这样，而今天我终于实现了
this. At 20 years old, I was crippled
。  20岁那年，我深受
with anxiety and fear about what others
焦虑和恐惧的折磨，害怕别人怎么
thought of me.
看我。   发生了
&gt;&gt; What changed? What happened? How did you
什么变化？ 发生了什么？ 你是如何
acquire such an aura? I think the aura
获得这种气场的？ 我认为这种光环
came from targeting, getting stats that
来自于目标明确，
I could prove that let somebody not see
我获得了可以证明的数据，让人们看不到我
me in my life choices, but actually let
的生活选择，而是
them see an outcome. So that first
看到了结果。 所以第一个
outcome was being able to recruit
成果就是能够招到
people. I wanted to actually have a stat
人。 我希望能够统计一下
that I have recruited X amount of
我已经招募了多少
people. Therefore, I know how to hire
人。 因此，我知道如何招聘
people. I know how to interview them. I
员工。 我知道如何采访他们。 我
know how to onboard them. I know how to
知道如何让他们顺利入职。 我知道如何
create a successful culture because a
打造成功的企业文化，因为
result shows that. So whether you like
结果证明了这一点。 所以不管你喜欢
me, don't like me, think that it was
我、不喜欢我，还是认为那是
him, you can't take away the stat. And I
他干的，你都无法改变这个统计数据。 我
became obsessed with not
开始执着于不去
getting things or doing things that took
得到任何东西，或者不去做任何会让
me away from stats.
我远离统计数据的事情。
&gt;&gt; So you needed to acquire first party
所以你需要获取
evidence for yourself about yourself.
关于你自己的第一手证据。
&gt;&gt; Mhm.
嗯。
&gt;&gt; So that within yourself, you knew
所以，在你内心深处，你清楚自己是
who you were
谁，
&gt;&gt; that
你对自己是谁有清晰的认识。
&gt;&gt; and even I guess to for people to do
而且我觉得，人们这样做也是
that because I'm sure there's so many
因为我相信有很多
people listening that are maybe
听众
20-year-old Natalie in some way, maybe a
在某种程度上就像20岁的娜塔莉一样，可能被
bit shrouded with sort certain
某种不
insecurities and maybe aren't the most
安全感所笼罩，可能不是最
conf confident, maybe a bit anxious,
自信的，可能有点焦虑，
scared about what people might think if
害怕如果尝试的话别人会怎么想
they try. What would you say to those
。
people from your experience?
以你的经验，你会对这些人说些什么？
&gt;&gt; Go all in on yourself.
全力以赴，相信自己。
Go all in on that weird thing that
全力投入到你感兴趣的那件看似古怪的事情上
you're interested in. If it's
。无论是
scrapbooking, if it's
剪贴簿制作、
social media, if it's
社交媒体、
recruiting, if you like reading business
招聘，还是喜欢阅读商业
books, go allin on that thing. And
书籍，都全力以赴。
social media has never created a better
社交媒体从未像现在这样，
time for people to actually create
为人们创造了更好的时代，让他们能够
incredible things based off of their own
根据自己的兴趣创造出令人惊叹的作品，
interests and get those things out to
并将这些作品传播到
the world. So 20-year-old, anybody,
世界各地。 所以，任何20岁的人，
anybody who is 20 years old should say,
任何20岁的人都应该说：
"This is what I'm interested in. It is
“这就是我感兴趣的事。它只有
one thing. It is not 12 things. And I'm
一件事，不是十二件事。我要全身心
going to go all in on myself with this
投入到这
thing and become completely obsessed and
件事中，完全痴迷其中，并围绕着它
create my environment around becoming
创造环境，让自己成为
the best at objectively the best at this
这件事上客观意义上的佼佼者
thing."
。”
&gt;&gt; Does it matter how you look? I've I've
外表重要吗？ 我曾在
heard you talk about this in a video you
你四月份制作的一个视频中听到过你谈到这一点，
made in April where you're talking about
你在视频中谈到了
seven steps to transforming yourself
自我改造的七个步骤，
&gt;&gt; and you say that you should rebrand your
你说你应该重新打造你的
look.
形象。
&gt;&gt; Does it matter how I look?
我的外貌重要吗？
&gt;&gt; I think it matters a lot to people how
我认为外表对人们来说非常重要
they look. I think people have a lot of
。 我认为人们对
levels of acceptance about how they look
自己的外貌接受程度有很多想法，
and ultimately you have to decide if you
最终你必须决定你是否对
are comfortable with the way that you
自己的外貌感到自在，
look and I do think many people
而且我确实认为很多人过分
overemphasize how they look and how they
强调自己的外貌和给人的印象
come across. But if you want to rebrand
。 但如果你想重新塑造
yourself and have this new identity,
自己的形象，拥有新的身份，
let's say somebody wants to go from
比如说，有人想从
being a 20-year-old college student that
一个20岁的大学生，一个
no one really takes seriously and it's
没人认真对待、有点
kind of dumpy and doesn't really like
邋遢、不喜欢
certain things but can't really
某些东西但又
articulate why. Spend too much time on
说不出为什么的人，变成一个全新的自己。 在社交媒体上花费的时间太多了
social media. And let's say that person
。 假设这个人
wants to become a professional golfer.
想成为一名职业高尔夫球手。
Well, all of a sudden, in order for me
突然间，为了
to become a professional golfer, the
成为一名职业高尔夫球手，
fastest way for me to be successful
我最快的成功途径
becoming a professional golfer is to
就是
practice golf every hour of the day and
每天每时每刻练习高尔夫，
to assimilate into that environment, to
融入那个环境，让自己看起来像个职业高尔夫球手，表现得像个职业高尔夫球手
look the part and to act the part. I'm a
。 我
huge believer in the process of be, do,
非常相信“存在、行动、
have. It is not have before you actually
拥有”的过程。 在你真正
be that person and you do the things in
成为那样的人之前，你不会拥有你想要的一切，你必须做那些事情才能
order to have the stuff or have the
拥有那些东西、那些
identity or have the whatever it is that
身份，或者那些
you're looking to create the being a
你想要创造的东西，比如成为一名
professional golfer, the scrapbooking
职业高尔夫球手、
business, the $20 million organization.
经营剪贴簿生意、创办价值 2000 万美元的组织。
And so the first step really is becoming
所以，第一步其实就是成为那样的人
that. And if I really want to change
。 如果我真的想改变
what my external environment is, I need
我的外部环境，我就需要
to get in those rooms and I need to
进入那些房间，并且
start to understand what those rooms
开始了解那些房间是什么样子
look like. And the fastest way for me to
。 对我来说，在
it doesn't compromise my moral code,
不违背我的道德准则的前提下，最快的实现方法就是
would be to start to look like, dress
开始让自己看起来像
like, act like that thing that I want to
我想成为的那种人，穿得像那种人，举止像那种人
become.
。
&gt;&gt; How important do you think communication
你认为沟通有多重要？
is in terms of like the way that you
比如你在
show up here and the way that you talk?
这里的表现方式和你的谈吐方式？
Do you think that's important? And if
你认为这重要吗？ 如果是
so, what advice would you give to to my
这样，您会给我的
audience about being an effective
听众提供哪些关于如何成为一名有效
communicator?
沟通者的建议？
&gt;&gt; Of course, communication is the most
当然，沟通是最
important thing. Next to being
重要的。 除了
successful,
成功之外，
actually, I would say in order to be
我认为要想
successful, you have to be able to
成功，你还必须能够
communicate your ideas and your thoughts
表达你的想法、观点、自我认知和立场
and who you are and your point of view.
。
And if you can't communicate those
如果你无法沟通这些
things, it will show in your inability
事情，就会体现在你无法
to create the things that you want to
创造你想要的东西上
have. So, what do you do when you think
。 那么，当你
about your own communication style? What
思考自己的沟通风格时，你会怎么做呢？
learned over time that are effective to
随着时间的推移，你学到了哪些能有效
make people take you seriously to to
使人们认真对待
hear you and to persuade people?
你、倾听你的意见并说服他人的方法？   无论
I am in. And that is a missed skill in a
身处哪个房间，我都能全神贯注。在如今
day and age where everyone has a cell
人人都拥有
phone where they can contact millions of
手机、可以瞬间联系到数百万人的时代，这反而成了一种稀缺的技能。
people instantly. I find that leaders
我发现，那些
who want to get promoted and and be in
想要晋升到
the next position, they don't even think
更高职位的领导者，根本不会意识到
of how unaware they look in every
自己在每次
leadership meeting because they are
领导会议上有多么茫然无措，因为他们
simply answering another email or not in
要么只是在回复邮件，要么根本不在
that room. And my philosophy is if
会议室里。 我的理念是，如果
you're in the room and your two feet are
你身处房间，双脚踏在
there, that is where you have to be. And
房间里，那么你就必须待在那里。
so you are an effective communicator if
所以，如果你能真正了解正在发生的事情，你就是一名有效的沟通者
happening. If I can track what he's
。 如果我能追踪他在
doing over here and when he comes and
这里做什么，以及他什么时候过来和
talks to me, I'm able to have a
我说话，我就可以和他
conversation because he's physically in
交谈，因为他实际上就在
my space. That communication matters.
我的空间里。 沟通至关重要。
in the room that matters in any room.
在任何房间里，重要的不仅仅是最重要的人。
It's how you present yourself to every
这关系到
individual because you are present in
你
that environment right now. And if you
此刻身处该环境中时，如何向每个人展现自己。 如果你
can teach yourself to not numb yourself
能学会不让自己对
from the environment, if you can teach
周围环境麻木，如果你能学会
yourself to really observe the
真正观察
environment and talk to whoever it is
周围环境，并与你面前的任何人交谈
that's in front of you, communicate with
，与
them, even if they're not talking to
他们沟通，即使他们没有和
you. How we became partners with Grant
你说话。 我们与格兰特和埃琳娜·卡多内成为合作伙伴的方式是，我们
and Elena Cardone was by sitting at an
参加了一个有
event with 35,000 people and instead of
35,000 人参加的活动，我们没有摆出一副高高在上、自以为是的样子
acting like we were somebody, we sat
，而是坐在
there in their audience and took notes
他们的观众席上，认真地做笔记，并对
they were saying. Why? Cuz if somebody's
他们所说的话表现出浓厚的兴趣。 为什么？ 因为如果有人
up on stage and you want that person's
在台上，你想引起那个人的
attention, the fastest way to make them
注意，最快让他们
not want to spend time with you is to
不想和你待在一起的方法就是懒散地坐在
slouch in your chair and is to look down
椅子上，低着头
or be distracted the whole time. And
或者一直心不在焉。
then when they meet you to come maybe
然后，当他们在活动结束时与你见面并可能与你
take a picture at the end of the event,
合影时，
they see you. They are going to know
他们就看到了你。 他们会知道
that you gave them no laughs, you gave
你没有逗他们笑，
them no verbal cues, you were completely
没有给他们任何言语上的暗示，完全
uninterested, and you actually made
没有兴趣，而且
their job harder for them despite the
尽管
fact that maybe they are your role model
他们可能是你的榜样
or idol. I find people are so unaware of
或偶像，你实际上还是让他们的工作更难了。 我发现人们常常意识不到
their physical presence in any room, in
自己在任何场合的存在，无论是在房间里、
a meeting, in a school room, in a
会议室里、教室里、
presentation, in a conversation with
演讲中、与伴侣交谈时，还是与
their significant other with their kids,
孩子相处时。
that if they could just own the space
如果他们能够真正掌控
that they are in and be intentional with
自己所处的空间，并有意识地关注
the human being that's in front of them
眼前这个人，那么他们的
would change everything in their lives.
人生将会彻底改变。
&gt;&gt; What about how you speak? how the very
你的说话方式如何？
the most effective speakers that you've
你遇到的最有影响力的演讲者
encountered, what it is they do
，他们在策略上做了什么，
tactically to make sure that people hear
才能确保人们听到
what they're saying and are persuaded by
他们所说的话并被
them, you know, and there's a spectrum,
他们说服？你知道，这其中存在一个范围，
right? There'll be these business owners
对吧？ 你会遇到一些企业主，他们的
communicators and speakers. What are
沟通和表达能力非常糟糕。
they doing wrong? And then the very best
他们做错了什么？ 然后，
that you meet, what are they doing
你遇到的最优秀的人，他们做对了什么
right?
？
frame their communication, I think helps
我认为，一个人拥有的沟通框架越多，就越有助于
them land their point. So there's no
他更好地表达自己的观点。 所以
shortages of frameworks on the planet.
地球上并不缺少框架。
My framework is vision, commitment,
我的框架是愿景、承诺、
execution. I use three steps in every
执行。 我会在每次沟通中都使用三个步骤，确保沟通有效
intentional about and wanting to land.
且达到预期效果。
And that three-step framework can be
这三步框架可以
used for getting a promotion. It could
用来获得晋升。 它可以
be used for laying people off. It could
用来裁员。 它可以
be used to figuring out where you're
用来决定
going to go to dinner that night and
当晚去哪里吃饭，并
persuading your significant other. So
说服你的另一半。 因此，
VCE is vision. And it's important that
VCE框架的第一步是愿景。
vision is first because if you can
愿景至关重要，因为如果你能向
articulate to somebody the intention and
别人清晰地表达
the why behind whatever it is you're
你所
communicating, you're going to get much
传达的意图和原因，你就能比
further than just going into tactics.
仅仅谈论战术走得更远。
&gt;&gt; I've heard you talk about avoiding
我听你说过要避免使用“
phrases like I think, I feel,
我认为”、“我觉得”、“
um, and being more high conviction and
嗯”之类的短语，并且在与人交流时要更有信心和
certain with the way that you
确定性
communicate with people.
。
&gt;&gt; Mh. Explain that to me.
嗯。 请你给我解释一下。   说
&gt;&gt; That honestly might be outdated for me.
实话，那对我来说可能已经过时了。   是的
&gt;&gt; Yeah.
。
&gt;&gt; Because in a day and age where it's
因为在如今这个
important to share your point of view,
分享观点很重要的时代，
it's not a bad thing to say, I think
说“我认为
this is the right path, especially if
这是正确的道路”并不是一件坏事，尤其是在
you aren't certain. And it
你不确定的时候。
[clears throat] shows strength and
（清嗓子）表明你表达了你的想法，这体现了你的力量和
integrity that you are
正直
this. you you don't know for sure and
。 你并不确定，
you're relying on other people. Now, if
只能依赖其他人。 如果
it is just a filler word, if somebody
这只是一个填充词，如果有人
says, "I think we should do this and
说，“我认为我们应该这样做，
this is the direction that I think we
我认为
should take Cardone Ventures," that
卡多内风险投资公司应该朝着这个方向发展”，那就
wouldn't be very engaging. So, in that
没什么吸引力了。 所以，在这种
context, you absolutely should not be
情况下，你绝对不应该
using these filler phrases of I think or
使用“我想”、“也许”之类的填充词，
maybe and and adding lack of certainty.
也不应该表示不确定。
At some level, you're playing a
在某种程度上，你是在和
certainty game with everybody around
周围的每个人玩一场确定性游戏
you, whether they are investors,
，无论他们是投资者、
clients, patients, team members,
客户、病人、团队成员、
partners, vendors. And so using phrases
合作伙伴还是供应商。 因此，使用会
that decrease people's certainty in your
降低人们对你
direction isn't going to help them help
方向的信心的措辞，并不能帮助他们帮助
you. But if you actually are uncertain,
你。 但如果你确实感到不确定，
it is okay to be transparent about that.
坦诚地说出来也无妨。
And it actually builds trust.
而且它确实能建立信任。
&gt;&gt; I think it's funny I just said I think I
我觉得挺搞笑的，我刚才居然说我经常会想到这个问题
think about this a lot. Um because I I
。 嗯，因为我
find myself writing out emails and
发现自己会把一些想法写进邮件和
messages where I've written I think in
信息里
them. And I I'd say 90% of the time
。 而且我估计90%的情况下都会
change it to I believe.
改成“我相信”。
&gt;&gt; And I think there's something different
我认为
about that framing. Whenever I write I
这种构图方式有所不同。 每当我写作时，我都感觉自己
believe it feels it's still appreciating
仍然在欣赏
that this is a belief that I have and I
这种信念，尽管我对
don't have certainty on this hypothesis.
这个假设并没有十足的把握。
But there's something high conviction
但是“
about the phrase I believe we're going
我相信我们会……”
to blah blah blah blah and I believe
和“我相信
that will happen blah blah. It feels
那将会发生……”这样的表达方式，却蕴含着一种高度的信念。 感觉
much better than I think. M
比我想象的要好得多。
&gt;&gt; I think I it's a bit flimsy.
我觉得它有点儿脆弱。
&gt;&gt; I'm in agreement with you.
我同意你的看法。
&gt;&gt; A bit plastic bag in the wind. So,
风中飘荡的一小块塑料袋。 所以，
&gt;&gt; but when you say it like this, it makes
当你这样说的时候，
me connect to you because it actually
我感觉和你产生了共鸣，因为这
feels like it's a stream of
感觉就像
consciousness that you are thinking
你在意识流中思考着
something.
什么。   是的
&gt;&gt; Yeah.
。   而不是
&gt;&gt; Instead of in an email.
通过电子邮件。
&gt;&gt; You saying I believe is much more
你说“我相信”更有
authoritative. I would
说服力。 我想
I would caution leaders when it comes to
提醒各位领导者，在
using words like I believe or being
使用“我相信”或“确信”之类的词语时，
certain about really ensuring that you
一定要确保你真的
are certain or you really do believe
确信或相信
something, especially as your business
某件事，尤其是在你的企业不断
grows. If you're doing a million dollars
发展壮大的时候。 如果你以前的公司年营业额是100万美元，
and now you have a $10 million business
现在变成了1000万美元，
and all of a sudden you have a a layer
而且突然之间你
of leaders around you, it can become an
身边多了好几层领导，那就会变成一个
echo chamber. And the more certain you
回音室。 你越自信
are, or at least you seem to be, the
，或者至少看起来越自信，
back on you when you might actually need
当你真正需要
them to collaborate. And you weren't so
他们合作时，人们就越不可能反对你。 你原本并不太
certain, but you came off with such
确定，但表现得却非常
certainty. And I find that that's a
自信。 我认为，随着
balance that leaders have to find as
领导者
they become more competent in their zone
在其擅长的领域变得更加胜任，随着
of genius and as they get higher up in
他们在
organizations or start their own
组织中职位越来越高，或者他们自己创办
organization themselves. if they aren't
组织，他们必须找到这种平衡。 如果他们不
really communicating what things they
真正沟通自己
aren't certain of but they're waffling
不确定的事情，而是含糊其辞，
on um it it can cause unnecessary
这可能会造成不必要的
duress.
压力。
&gt;&gt; You talk about mastering your calendar
你谈到掌控你的日程安排
as well being central transformation.
也是核心变革的一部分。
&gt;&gt; Why is why is this so important and what
为什么这件事如此重要？
does that mean?
这意味着什么？
&gt;&gt; Well, if you want anything in life, you
嗯，如果你想要生活中得到任何东西，你
actually have to spend time to get that
实际上都需要花时间去争取
thing. things don't just magically
。 尽管互联网上充斥着各种各样的说法，但事物并不会凭空
manifest into people's lives despite
出现在人们的生活中
what the internet tells you. So, in
。 所以，
order for me to have the relationship
为了拥有
that I want to have, I actually have to
我想要的恋爱关系，我必须
invest time with my significant other.
投入时间陪伴我的另一半。
that I'm going to have an amazing
我的美满
marriage. If I want to have great
婚姻不会凭空出现。 如果我想拥有
friends, I actually have to spend time
好朋友，我就必须花时间
with my friends. And so your calendar is
陪伴我的朋友。 因此，你的日历
a reflection and a representation of
反映并代表了
what you find to be important and is in
你认为重要的事情，以及这些事情是否
alignment or out of alignment with the
与
goals that you have every single day. So
你每天的目标一致。 所以，
if I have zero time being spent on
如果我没有花任何时间在
generating revenue inside my business,
我的企业内部创造收入，那么到
the year that I'm doing the same amount
年底我的
of revenue that I did last year. Why? I
收入与去年持平也就不足为奇了。 为什么？ 我没有
spent zero time on the one thing aka
花任何时间在最重要的事情上，也就是
revenue generation in order for it to
创收方面，让它
grow. So for me, my calendar, and I
发展壮大。 所以对我来说，我的日历，也是我
day, you have to look at it every day.
每天都教给企业主的，你必须每天都看它。
You you have to start to align your
你必须开始安排好自己的
time, unless you want your life to be
时间，除非你想让自己的生活
something that just is a story of luck.
仅仅成为一段靠运气的故事。
I don't know about you, but I'm not
我不知道你怎么想，但我对
interested in having a life of luck
一帆风顺的生活不感兴趣，
because I think that actually leads to a
因为我认为那实际上会导致
significant amount of self-doubt and
大量的自我怀疑和
uncertainty. Oh, just because I'm lucky,
不确定感。 哦，就因为我运气好，
I'm going to leave something to to being
我就要把一些事情归咎于
out of my control just because I I
我无法控制的事情，仅仅因为我
happen to be at the right place at the
碰巧在
right time. Of course, there are those
正确的时间出现在了正确的地点。 当然，这些
components. I have been at the right
因素都包含在内。 在
place at the right time throughout my
我的
career. But the way that you control
职业生涯中，我一直都恰逢其时，出现在了正确的地点。 但是，如果你有目标和抱负，想要过上与现在不同的生活，那么你掌控
where you spend your time gives you the
自己时间的方式就能为你提供
most amount of atbats to the
最多的机会去争取
opportunities that you want if you have
你想要的机会
different life than you currently have.
。   直到
And to me, still to this day, I want to
今天，我仍然希望
have a different life in the future. And
未来能过上不一样的生活。
I imagined a more enriched version of my
我设想了自己
life at 40 and at 50 and at 60. And I
40岁、50岁、60岁时更加充实的生活。我
think if people were really honest with
想，如果人们真的对
themselves, they want a different
自己诚实，他们也想要另一种
version of their lives, too. I don't
生活。 我不
think someone listens to this podcast or
认为有人听这个播客或
watches this show without wanting to be
看这个节目时，不想成为
something different or to have something
不同的人，或者想拥有
different, whether it's relationship or
不同的事物，无论是人际关系、
different health situation or different
健康状况、
income, different friends. I mean, how
收入还是朋友。 我的意思是，有
many people would want different
多少人想要结交一些与众不同的
friends, like badass friends to do cool
朋友，比如那种可以一起做很酷事情的超酷朋友
[__] with? Well, how do you get that?
？ 那么，你如何才能得到它呢？
Okay, I would need to actually reverse
好吧，我需要反向
engineer using my time and what I do
推导，利用我每天所做的事情和我的时间，
every single day to get me closer to
来让我更接近
people who are doing those similar
那些做类似
things. And so, that might actually take
事情的人。 所以，
me making sacrifices for 2 years in
我可能真的需要做出两年的牺牲，
order to be able to be around people, to
才能与人相处，才能为
be able to give value to people who'd be
那些有
interested in being my friend. And it
兴趣和我做朋友的人带来价值。 这
sounds a little
听起来有点像
strategic, but it is because you don't
策略，但事实的确如此，因为你不会仅仅
because you happen to be at the right
因为恰好在
place at the right time. You get great
正确的时间出现在正确的地点就遇到优秀的人。 要想招到优秀的
people by doing great things because
人才，就要去做伟大的事，因为
great people want to spend time around
优秀的人才都愿意和
other people who are doing great things.
那些正在做伟大事的人在一起。   要想确保
know that you are doing great things
自己能够做出伟大的事情，
without getting lucky or happening to
而不靠运气或外表吸引别人
invited into certain places is by
邀请你进入某些地方，唯一的办法就是
managing and really creating your own
管理和真正创造自己的
time.
时间。
&gt;&gt; What about hard work in this equation?
在这个等式中，努力工作又扮演着怎样的角色呢？
You know, people talk a lot about work
你知道，人们经常谈论工作与
life balance and I think a lot of people
生活的平衡，我认为很多人都
want want everything. We want to, you
想要一切。 你知道，我们想要到了
know, get to 40, have the yacht, have
40岁，拥有游艇，拥有
the great family, have great
美满的家庭，拥有良好的
relationships, have a great business. I
人际关系，拥有成功的事业。 我的
mean, that's an ideal outcome for all of
意思是，这对我们所有人来说都是理想的结果
us. What would you say to people about
。 你会对人们说些什么关于
the concept of working hard and how
努力工作这个概念，以及
critical or or unimportant that is?
它究竟有多重要或多不重要？
&gt;&gt; Working hard is the most important
努力工作是最重要的
thing. You cannot get to where you want
。 如果你要去的地方真的
unusual or out of the ordinary without
非同寻常或非同寻常，那么
working hard. Never burnout inducing
不努力奋斗是不可能到达的。 但绝不会让人感到疲惫
though. And I think that that's a
。 我认为这是
misconception about hard work. I don't
对努力工作的误解。 我不
know successful people who are still in
认识任何一位仍在职场上取得成功的人，
the game who are burnt out by a long
他们会因为
day. That the response isn't burnout.
一天工作下来而感到筋疲力尽。 那并不是职业倦怠。
Their their response might be, I want to
他们的回应可能是：我想
go do something different for a minute.
暂时做点别的事情。
But my business partner, Grant Cardone,
但我非常敬佩我的商业伙伴格兰特·卡多内，
who I am obsessed with, and that was one
那是
of the greatest partnerships I could
我一生中最棒的合作之一。
have ever done in my entire life, he
他
says, "You're not a candle. You can't
说：“你不是蜡烛，你不会燃尽
burn out. A human being cannot burn out
。人不会燃尽，
because you are not a candle. So, can
因为你不是蜡烛。那么，
you feel moments of pressure, stress?"
你能感受到压力和紧张吗？”   是的
Yes. I don't take any of those moments
。 我不认为那些时刻是件
as being a bad thing. It's not a
坏事。
negative to feel overwhelmed because you
因肩负重任而感到压力过大并非坏事
have responsibility. People depend on
。 人们都依赖
you. People are relying on you to do
你。 人们指望你成就一番
something great. Go.
伟业。 去。
&gt;&gt; Burnout then in your view. Why do people
你认为这就是职业倦怠吗？ 为什么人们会
say, do you know I was doing this thing
说，“你知道吗，我当时在做这件事，结果
and I got burnt out so I had what is
筋疲力尽，然后我就……”
that?
？
&gt;&gt; The thing that people do is not actually
人们所做的事情实际上并不
leading to where they want to go.
能让他们到达想去的地方。
So, if I thought that it was going to
所以，如果我认为要
require me to work out two hours a day
练出六块腹肌就必须每天
in the gym and only eat chicken and rice
在健身房锻炼两个小时，只能吃鸡肉和米饭，
and never have any of the things that I
永远不能吃任何我
love to never get a six-pack, I'm not
喜欢的东西，那我肯定不会
going to do that. But if I think that by
这么做。 但是，如果我认为通过
doing this work that's going to be hard
做这项工作会很辛苦，
and I'm gonna hate and it's going to
我会讨厌它，而且会很糟糕，但
suck that I can actually get what I want
我实际上可以得到我想要的东西，
and my life would be changed because I'd
我的生活将会改变，因为我会
actually have a six-pack and I'd feel
拥有六块腹肌，我会感到
confident and I'd be able to buy the
自信，我可以买
clothes that I'd want and I'd just be
我想要的衣服，我将成为
population that has one. Then the
拥有六块腹肌的极少数人中的一员。 这样一来，
process of me going to the gym early at
我在
5:00 before my kids get up wouldn't burn
孩子们起床前，早上 5 点去健身房锻炼就不会让
me out. I would recognize that this is a
我筋疲力尽了。 我意识到这是
step that's necessary to get to my goal.
实现目标的必要步骤。
And at which point when the goal is
而当目标
there, you might change your mind and
达成时，你可能会改变主意，设定
you might have a different goal. But
一个不同的目标。 但当
when people win, they are rarely burnt
人们获得胜利时，他们很少会
out at that moment. I've watched
在那一刻感到筋疲力竭。 我亲眼见过
business owners sell their businesses
企业主以数亿美元的价格出售他们的企业
for hundreds of millions of dollars. Uh
。 呃，
I've watched them get hundreds of
我亲眼看着他们
millions of dollars in their bank
银行账户里多了数亿美元
account. And that feeling of celebration
。 这种庆祝
and joy happens to stay around for a
和喜悦的感觉会持续
little while until that thing kicks in,
一段时间，直到某种东西开始发挥作用，
which is that individual's potential to
那就是这个人
help somebody, to solve more problems,
帮助他人、解决更多问题、
to be able to make a larger impact. And
产生更大影响的潜力。
so that end goal does end up moving. The
因此，最终目标确实发生了变化。
goalpost ends up moving. And there's
球门柱最终被移动了。 这
actually nothing wrong with that.
其实没什么错。
despite the world wanting to tell you
尽管全世界都想告诉你，
fact that you're moving the goalpost. I
你改变比赛规则是不对的。 我
don't think there's anything wrong with
觉得没什么问题
it. And you only really get burnt out if
。 只有当
you don't see how the sacrifices that
你看不到
you're making are actually going to lead
自己所做的牺牲最终会如何帮助
you to the six-pack. If you're going to
你练出六块腹肌时，你才会真正感到筋疲力竭。 如果你注定要
be overweight forever, then of course
永远超重，那
I'm just going to eat candy and chips
我当然要吃糖果、薯片
and all the things that I love to eat.
以及所有我爱吃的东西了。
But I do think I could get a six-pack.
但我认为我可以练出六块腹肌。
So, I'm willing to make some of these
所以，我愿意做出一些
sacrifices here and there because the
牺牲，因为这个
goal isn't going to allow me to get
目标不会让我
burnt out because I'm going to be so
筋疲力尽，因为当
freaking proud of myself by the time I
我达到目标时，我会为自己感到无比自豪，
reach that goal, at which point I'm
到那时我
going to change it to a different goal.
会把它改成另一个目标。
and exciting of a game for me to play at
对我来说，在人生的那个阶段玩这款游戏也同样会是一件有趣而令人兴奋的事情
that point in my life.
。
&gt;&gt; Do you think people respect you a lot
你觉得
more now at 33 than they did when you
现在33岁的你比
in 2019?
2019年的时候更受人们尊重吗？
&gt;&gt; Of course they do.
当然会。
&gt;&gt; And what should someone do that is
那么，想要赢得尊重的人应该怎么做呢
looking to earn the respect? some
？ 有些
someone that feels like they're
人觉得自己
continually disrespected. There's
一直受到不尊重。 他们身上有种特别的气质
something about them. There's something
。 他们的举止中透露出一种感觉，那就是他们
what they continually feel like people
不断觉得别人不
are disrespecting them. They might work
尊重他们。 他们可能
in a business or, you know, they might
在一家企业工作，或者，你知道，他们可能
be low down in a company or maybe
在公司里职位很低，也可能都不是
they're not. Maybe they're just someone
。 也许他们只是在
who's gone through the corporate world
企业界摸爬滚打多年，却一直得不到
and they're continually disrespected.
尊重的人。
What would you say they should do to to
你认为他们应该怎么做才能
earn people's respect?
赢得人们的尊重？   要想
order to earn respect is to decide that
赢得尊重，首先要做的就是下定决心，
they would rather be respected than
宁愿被人尊重而不是被人
liked. That trade-off is made too often.
喜欢。 这种权衡取舍的情况太常见了。
We're in a situation when the right
我们现在面临的情况是，真正
respectful thing to do is unlikable. We
尊重他人的做法却令人反感。 我们
don't choose the right respectable thing
没有选择做正确且体面的事情
to do. We prioritize being liked. And so
。 我们非常重视别人是否喜欢我们。 所以，
when you make that decision to be
当你决定要赢得
respected and to not prioritize what
尊重，不再在意
everybody thinks about you, you can then
别人对你的看法时，你就可以
transition into the second step, which
进入第二步，那就是在
that you want respect in. If you're low
你想要赢得尊重的领域取得成绩。如果你
in an organization or you have different
在组织中地位不高，或者你
people around you who don't respect you
周围的人
for a variety of different reasons, what
因为各种原因不尊重你，那么
is the area of your expertise that is
你有哪些无可争议的专业领域呢
undeniable?
？
It's proof. It exists in the physical
这就是证据。 它存在于物质
universe. It's not just because you had
世界之中。 这不仅仅是因为你有
an idea or you think you can be an
一个想法，或者你认为自己可以成为一名
entrepreneur or you'd like to be someone
企业家，或者你想成为一名为
who gives people relationship advice.
人们提供情感建议的人。   很
I'm sorry, but if you're not in a
抱歉，但如果你
relationship and you don't have a stat
单身，又没有
of being able to have a good
建立良好
relationship and you can't have a spouse
关系的能力，也无法拥有一个让你觉得
that's like, "Wow, this person's great.
“哇，这个人真棒。
I love being around this person." You
我喜欢和这个人在一起”的伴侣。 你
probably shouldn't be giving that advice
或许不应该给出那样的建议，
and that's why you don't have respect in
这就是为什么你在
that area. So, I don't think respect is
这一领域得不到尊重的原因。 所以，我认为尊重并不是指对
a overall life respect. You need to have
生活的全面尊重。 你需要
respect in the different compartments.
尊重不同的群体。
It's not just Steven is a respectable
史蒂文不仅仅是一个值得尊敬的
person altogether. That's that's a
人。 在
facade to me. You might not be
我看来，那只是伪装。 你
respectable in certain areas. I maybe
在某些方面可能不被人尊重。 我或许
shouldn't respect you in certain areas
不应该在你生活的某些方面尊重你
of your life,
，
&gt;&gt; but other areas, I would think areas
但在其他方面，我认为
that you've prioritized, you're
你非常重视的那些方面，你
incredibly respectable in, and you've
非常值得尊敬。你
prioritized getting stats and proof in
重视在这些方面获得数据和证据，
those areas to earn people's respect
以赢得人们的尊重，
whether they like you or not, because
无论他们是否喜欢你，因为
you have something to prove for it.
你在这方面有所成就。
&gt;&gt; Has that been a journey for you, this
你是否也经历了一段转变，才有了
idea of caring less about being liked?
不再那么在意别人喜欢你的想法？
Because you talked about that earlier as
因为你之前说过，那对
being really central to your sort of
你二十出头的年纪来说非常重要
early 20ies, etc. It was so hard for me
等等。对我来说，
to not want to be liked. I had a mom
不想被人喜欢真的很难。 我从小就有一位身为医生的母亲，她
just was the world's most sweet, kind,
是世界上最温柔、最善良、最
thoughtful person. She would sit down at
体贴的人。 她只要一坐到
a party and every single person in that
聚会上，房间里的每个人都会
room loved her immediately that she just
立刻喜欢上她，因为她身上
had this aura about her. And so I
有一种独特的气质。 因此，我
watched my mom growing up as a role
看着我的母亲成长为我的
model and somebody who still to me today
榜样，直到今天她仍然
is a role model. and she really
是我的榜样。 她非常
emphasized how important it is to ask
强调提出
great questions and to be engaged with
好问题和与
other people. And what I lost in that
他人互动的重要性。 在这个过程中，我失去了的是
process is well, if I'm always asking
，如果我总是要求
other people and and trying to get other
别人喜欢我，总是试图让
people to like me and it's always that
别人喜欢我，总是陷入这种
flow, like what do I actually think
状态，那么我究竟是如何看待
about myself because I'm so focused on
自己的呢？因为我太专注于
over accommodating others? And so if
过度迎合别人了。 所以，如果
you're trying to flip this for yourself,
你想改变这种想法，
you're trying to go from I overindex on
你就会想从“我过分在意别人
being liked and not so overindexed on
喜欢我”，而不再过分在意别人尊重我，也不再那么
being respectable and liking what I
喜欢自己
think about myself. You really have to
对自己的看法。 你真的需要好好想想
go out to your three-year version of
三年后的
yourself and your 5-year version of
自己和五年后的
yourself because no one is going to get
自己，因为
clear on that for you besides you. And
除了你自己，没有人能替你弄清楚这一点。
once you put that stake in the ground
一旦你明确了自己的目标：
saying, "This is what I want to be known
“这就是我想被人记住的
for. this is who I want to become. This
，这就是我想成为的人，这
is who I imagine myself being. This
就是我梦想中的自己。”这
isn't a manifestation practice. It's a
并非一种显化练习，而是
I'm going to decide who that person is.
我要决定自己成为怎样的人。
And then I'm going to like myself at 20,
那么，无论20岁、
at 30, at 70 because I'm acting in
30岁还是70岁，我都会喜欢现在的自己，因为我的行为与我对
myself in the future and I'm going to
未来的自我认知相符，我将成为
become the person that I want to be.
我想成为的人。
&gt;&gt; Have you found that you've had to
你是否发现，
reinforce and protect your boundaries in
为了赢得尊重，你必须强化并捍卫自己的界限
order to earn that respect? Do you find
？你是否发现
that people try and test you? Of course
人们会试图试探你？当然
they do. I work with hundreds of team
会。我每天都与数百名团队
members every single day who have their
成员共事，他们对工作和企业文化都有着
own points of view and their own
各自的观点和
perspectives on what they want the work
看法
to look like. And I think I've had to
。我认为我之所以需要为此苦苦
wrestle with this so much because I want
挣扎，是因为我想
to create an environment where people
创造一个让每个人
can be successful. My definition of
都能获得成功的环境。我对
leadership is making other people's
领导力的定义是让别人的
success easy. So, if I'm going to be a
成功变得轻松。所以，如果我要成为一名
leader, I'm going to make other people's
领导者， 我要让别人更
success easy. How would I go about doing
容易成功。我该怎么做呢
that? What type of environment would
？他们需要什么样的环境才能
they need to be in in order to actually
真正
make their success easy compared to
轻松地获得成功，而不是像现在这样，
their alternative, which is going down
去
the street and trusting that some other
街对面找个
leader is going to make them more
领导，指望他能让他们更
successful. And so, I really wrestle
成功？所以，我一直在
with who I need to be and what the
纠结自己应该成为什么样的人，以及
boundaries are that I set for myself.
我为自己设定的界限是什么。
And one of the things I've gotten so
我在网上受到很多批评的一件事，是
much criticism of uh online was when I
我
publicly shared a Tik Tok about firing
公开分享了一个TikTok视频，内容是关于我解雇了
somebody because I found out that she
一名员工，因为我发现她
was cheating on her significant other
出轨了，
and the other person also had a
而且另一个人也有
significant other. And as soon as I
伴侣。我一
found out about it, I terminated both of
发现这件事，就
them immediately. And it's so shocking
立刻解雇了他们俩。这让
to people that
很多人感到震惊：
&gt;&gt; Wait, someone was cheating with someone
等等，有人
in the company?
在公司里出轨？
&gt;&gt; Yeah.
是的。
&gt;&gt; Oh, and they both had partners outside
哦，而且他们俩在公司外都有伴侣
company. As soon as I caught wind of it,
。我一知道这件事，就立刻做出了
decision. Well, I guess it technically
决定。好吧，严格来说，这确实
was a split-second decision. Was like, I
是瞬间的决定。就像，我 我
can't have this in my environment,
不能容忍这种事发生在我的环境中，
especially somebody close around me.
尤其是我身边的人。
People trust me and should trust any
人们信任我，也应该信任任何
leader to help them make their success
领导者，相信他们能帮助他们轻松取得成功
easy. Am I making people's success easy
。如果我把那些会破坏团队价值观的人放在我的环境中，我就能让人们更容易成功吗
of the group? No. Success for most
？当然不能。对大多数
people isn't getting a divorce from
人来说，成功不是和
their significant other. Success for
伴侣离婚。成功
most people looks like figuring out how
意味着
to have the success in their
在
professional lives and in their
事业和
financial lives while also being able to
经济上取得成功，同时还能
have a spouse. I wouldn't want my
拥有美满的婚姻。我不希望我的
husband going out to work and being in
丈夫去上班，却身处一个
just fine with people cheating on each
对员工出轨
other, lying to each other, and not
、撒谎、没有
having a code of ethics, doing drugs.
道德准则、吸毒等行为都习以为常的环境中。这些
Like none of that is something that I
我都不
want inside my environment cuz it's my
希望出现在我的环境中，因为我的
job to make people's success easy.
职责就是帮助人们轻松成功。
&gt;&gt; One would say that's none of your
有人会说，
business what they're doing when they go
他们回家做什么与你无关
home.
。但
&gt;&gt; It is my business first of all because
首先，这当然与我有关，因为
it was with each other.
那是他们之间的事。
&gt;&gt; Yeah. But they're not doing it at work.
没错。但他们不是在工作场所做这些事。
&gt;&gt; Well, there was a not to get into
好吧，具体
specifics of the particular event, but
细节就不说了，但
it happened to be around work related.
事情确实发生了。 在工作场合，出轨当然是必须的。
&gt;&gt; But but if it wasn't at work, you still
但即便不是在工作场合，
&gt;&gt; even if it was, I would fire the person
我也会立即解雇这个人
immediately.
。
&gt;&gt; So you'd fire someone for cheating.
所以，如果有人出轨，我肯定会解雇他。
Absolutely. On their
绝对会。背叛
&gt;&gt; partner. Absolutely.
伴侣？绝对会。
&gt;&gt; I can't have cheaters. If they're going
我不能容忍出轨的人。如果他们要背叛自己
supposed to spend the rest of their life
应该共度余生的人
with, do you think that they're cheating
，你觉得他们会背叛
on their work?
工作吗？
&gt;&gt; Do you think that they're going to cheat
你觉得他们会
on our clients? Do you think that
背叛我们的客户吗？你觉得
they're going to have the ethics and
他们会有足够的道德、
morals and judgment to not be so
伦理和判断力，不被
distracted with their own personal
自己的私事分心，从而
ethics situation that they can actually
能够集中精力
focus and do a good job? That person in
做好工作吗？这样的人在
any environment is a liability to the
任何环境下都是
environment. It's a complete liability.
环境的累赘。绝对是累赘。
Some people have, you know, things in
有些人
their personal life which are very
私生活和
professionally. Though people people do
职业形象截然不同。虽然人们
all kinds of things in their personal
在私生活中会做各种各样的事情
life.
。
&gt;&gt; It's terrifying
这很可怕，
&gt;&gt; cuz listen, the way that I see it is if
因为听着，我的看法是，如果
I expand the scope of my uh [laughter]
我扩大我的担忧范围，呃[笑]
&gt;&gt; I'm going to get [__] nothing done.
我他妈的什么事都做不成了。
&gt;&gt; Mhm. So if I start, you know, going into
嗯。所以，如果我开始，你知道，去管
who they who they at home with and in
他们跟谁在家、跟谁
bed with and what's going on in their
上床，以及他们的
personal life, unless they bring it to
私生活，除非他们主动告诉
me, obviously when you're the founder or
我，显然，当你是创始人或
the CEO, people bring you stuff and they
CEO的时候，人们会把事情告诉你，他们会
say, "Look, this is going to impact my
说，“听着，这会影响我的
work."
工作。”
&gt;&gt; But um I, you know, boundary, I don't
但是，嗯，你知道，界限，我不想，
want to be I don't want to be the
我不想
government of your [__] personal
干涉你们的
situations as well, as long as it
私生活，只要它
doesn't show up in the office.
不影响到工作就行。
&gt;&gt; Mhm.
嗯。
&gt;&gt; If you've ever worked in a startup, you
如果你在创业公司工作过，你
already know it's chaos. It's speed and
就知道那里很混乱。节奏很快，
it is survival. And now with AI
生存至关重要。现在，随着人工智能
accelerating everything, that speed has
加速一切，这种速度只会
only increased. Startups are landing
更快。创业公司比以往任何时候都
enterprise deals even earlier than
更早地拿下企业订单
before. But what comes with those deals
。但这些订单也带来了
is regulatory requirements. Something a
监管要求。
lot of earlystage businesses aren't
很多早期企业都没有
equipped to handle. And a sock too, if
能力应对这些要求。而且，如果
you know what that means, isn't always
你明白我的意思，仅仅靠一双袜子是
enough. When having the right kind of
不够的。拥有合适的
security is the difference between
安全措施是
making a deal or breaking a deal, you
成败的关键。 无论是达成交易还是取消交易，你都
need to have a plan in place. Vanta, who
需要制定计划。Vanta
are a sponsor of this podcast, have an
是本播客的赞助商，他们拥有一套
AI and automation system that makes it
人工智能和自动化系统，可以帮助你
easier to meet buyer expectations in
在短短几天内轻松满足买家的期望
just days. And they continuously monitor
。他们还会持续监控
your compliance so any future deals are
你的合规情况，确保未来的交易
never blocked. With AI changing
不会受阻。随着人工智能不断改变
regulations, their team knows exactly
监管法规，他们的团队能够准确把握
what's needed and when it's needed. And
需求以及何时需要。
they've built the fastest and easiest
他们已经为你打造了最快捷、最简便的
path to get you there. If you're running
途径。如果你正在运营
a startup and this appeals to you, you
一家初创公司，并且对这套系统感兴趣，
can visit vanta.com/ceo
可以访问 vanta.com/ceo
and get $1,000 off. That's vanta.com/ceo
享受 1000 美元的优惠。访问 vanta.com/ceo 即可享受
for $1,000 off.
1000 美元的优惠。
If I'm thinking of starting a business
如果我计划
in 2025,
在 2025 年创业，
you know, you've spoken to thousands and
你知道，你已经
owners online, probably many millions of
在线上与成千上万的企业主交流过，可能数以百万计
business owners.
。
When we think about that initial period
当我们思考最初的阶段，
of like coming up with the idea and
比如构思想法和
picking what to work on. Is there any
选择工作方向时，
advice you would give people based on
基于
the success and failure you've seen
你所看到的成功和失败案例，你有什么建议可以给人们，告诉他们
about what they should aim at, what they
应该朝着什么方向努力，应该做什么
should work on, especially in the
，尤其是在……
context of like 2025 when so much in the
2025年，
world is changing so quickly?
世界瞬息万变，
&gt;&gt; If they could use the frame, if any
如果所有
business owner or potential business
企业主或潜在企业
owner could think about starting a
主都能运用“
business from the standpoint of where is
哪里
there the greatest chance for me to be
最有可能
successful, that is the best frame to
成功”这一框架来思考创业，那将是最佳选择
use. Unfortunately, most do not use that
。可惜的是，大多数人并没有采用这种
frame and they base it off of their
框架，而是基于自身
existing experience and the skills that
现有的经验和技能
they have. If it was not based off of
。我认为，如果创业不再基于
existing experience or skills that
经验或技能，那么
somebody has, I think great AI is going
强大的人工智能将
to be the great leveler because nobody
成为真正的平衡器，因为目前
has a lot of experience in AI. Nobody
人工智能领域经验尚浅。
knows in small businesses across America
在美国，许多小企业都不知道如何
how to hook up automations and start
搭建自动化系统，如何
working with assistants to be able to
与助手协作，从而将
put small businesses onto a CRM system
企业接入客户关系管理系统（CRM）
or an operating system that connects to
或与
their financial software that allows the
财务软件连接的操作系统，帮助
business owner to make great decisions.
企业主做出明智的决策。此前，
No one has done this at scale because it
由于缺乏此类技术，没有人能够大规模地实现这一点
didn't exist. And so if I was starting a
。因此，如果我
business in 2025, I would absolutely
在2025年创业，我一定会
look at how do I help business owners
思考如何帮助那些
who have an infinite budget for things
拥有无限预算、希望通过真正有效的方法
that actually work to make them more
增加
money solve problems that are real to
收入的企业主解决他们面临的
them. And the problems that are real to
实际问题。
United States of America is that they
美国有3500万企业主
don't know how to use AI. they are
不知道如何使用人工智能。他们
terrified of AI and they're going to
对人工智能感到恐惧，要么选择
either put their head in the sand or
视而不见，要么寄希望于
assume that somebody who is young is
年轻人能为他们找到
going to create the solution for them
解决方案。然而，经验丰富的
when somebody instead who is experienced
人如果能真正找到解决这些问题的方法，或许
could have a eight maybe even a nine
能在未来18到24个月内打造一个八位数甚至九
figure business over the course of the
位数的企业，
how to help solve these problems because
因为
it makes the business owner to that
这能让企业主与
business incredibly sticky. the customer
客户之间建立起极强的粘性。客户
is always going to be there and they
始终存在，而他们
would be on the front end of something
将站在一个
that nobody has experience in.
无人涉足领域的前沿。
&gt;&gt; So do you think a lot about this the
所以，当你考虑在哪里开店创业时，你会不会过多考虑
speed in which that market is growing
这个市场的增长速度
shop and start a business?
？
&gt;&gt; Of course the market growth is
当然，市场增长
everything because if you want to start
至关重要。如果你想
a paper business in 2025, you would have
在2025年开一家造纸企业，你必须
to be the best paper business and really
成为业内最好的造纸企业，并
have a unique positioning to make that
拥有独特的市场定位才能
successful. when you could do something
成功。而现在，即使你做得
less well and be much more successful
没那么好，也能获得更大的成功，
because there's just more opportunity in
因为市场增长带来的机遇更多，
the growth and there's less players in
竞争者也更少
markets. So the growth allows for
。所以，增长带来了更多可能。 就
innovation, the growth allows for new
创新而言，增长为新
entrance and as I mentioned with AI, uh
进入者提供了机会，正如我之前提到的人工智能，
opportunity in front of people right
现在人们面前就摆着前所未有的机遇
now. But I'm also very excited about
。但我同样对
service-based businesses, roofers,
服务型企业，比如屋顶工、
plumbers, electricians,
水管工、电工、
HVAC, all of those businesses.
暖通空调工等等，感到非常兴奋。在
disrupted by AI until robots. But those
机器人出现之前，人工智能不会颠覆这些企业的核心业务。但这些
business operations are ripe for
业务的运营已经成熟，可以吸引
somebody to come in, I don't care if
新人进入，我不在乎
you're 15 years old or if you're 50
你是15岁还是50
years old, and get paid tens of
岁，你可以利用人工智能为这些企业实施一些真正能解决问题的简单方案，
thousands of dollars per client to
每个客户就能获得数万美元的报酬。
&gt;&gt; Yeah. I've heard you talk about when you
是的，我听你说过，
businesses that you think will be around
你认为到2026年，六大最赚钱的企业将会存在。
in 2026. We've talked about AI
我们谈到了人工智能
businesses, talked about home services.
企业、家庭服务，还有
The other one was hybrid wellness clubs.
混合型健康俱乐部。
&gt;&gt; Mhm.
嗯。
&gt;&gt; Why is why is health such a a big
为什么
predict prediction for you in terms of
你认为健康领域在
profitability and a good place to set up
盈利能力和
shop?
创业方面如此重要？在
co the whole world changed and their
世界发生巨变之后，健康领域正在蓬勃发展。 人们的
priorities changed as it relates to
优先事项随着
health. the statistics I read recently
健康而改变。我最近读到一些关于夜总会等场所酒类销售的统计数据，情况已经大不相同了。人们不再像以前那样
used to be because instead of wanting to
喜欢熬夜狂欢，而是更加注重
prioritizing their health and providing
健康。为了帮助他们
them with solutions for optimizing their
优化健康，人们一直在寻求各种解决方案。自那时以来，这种趋势一直在持续
health is just it's continued to grow
增长，
for ever since co and it's going to
而且随着
amenities at gyms with different types
健身房提供各种设施和各种
of technology that people are inserting
技术，这种趋势还将继续增长。
into what a traditional I one time I
我
recently went to a a facial, my favorite
最近去做了一次面部护理，这是我最喜欢的
thing, my hobby. I went to get a
事情，也是我的爱好。我去做了一个
60-minute facial and they integrated IV
60分钟的面部护理，他们把静脉输液
services into that facial experience.
服务融入到了面部护理体验中。
Well, what else could you do that allows
那么，还有什么方法可以让
somebody who is sitting in a chair for
坐在椅子上
60 minutes to add revenue to that
60分钟的人为这家与
business that's connected to their
他们的
health and well-being? Those types of
健康和福祉相关的企业增加收入呢？这类
innovations are happening in small
创新正在
markets all across the world.
世界各地的小市场中发生。
&gt;&gt; And why did you say in that video pet
你为什么在视频中提到宠物
care?
护理？
&gt;&gt; People love their pets and people will
人们爱他们的宠物，人们愿意
spend money on their pets. People will
为宠物花钱。人们
spend more money on their pets than
在宠物身上花的钱比其他任何东西都多。
they'll spend on their kids and then
他们会为孩子花钱，也会
they'll spend on themselves. I mean, if
为自己花钱。我的意思是，如果
somebody has a dog, I recently talked to
有人养狗，我最近和一位
somebody who told me that she was doing
女士聊天，她说她正在给
Reiki with her 12 dogs. I mean, it's
她的12只狗做灵气疗法。我的意思是，
people have in taking care of their
人们对照顾
pets. I think what's happened in that
宠物的热情真的很高。我认为，在这个
market place specifically is as business
市场中，随着企业主和
owners and high-income earners make more
高收入人群
money and they do have these pets, these
收入的增加，他们也养宠物，这些
things that are dependent upon them that
宠物虽然还不是孩子，但却依赖着他们
aren't yet children. They want to spend
。他们想把
their discretionary income on making
可支配收入花在让
that pooch that is their new best friend
自己的新朋友——狗狗——感到
phto comfortable
舒适健康上，提供
making him be well through all sorts of
各种各样的
offerings because I feel bad and it can
服务，因为他们觉得对不起它，而给它找个照料者、涂
phto with a caretaker and nail polish
指甲油、做
EMF, you know, therapy.
电磁场疗法之类的，可以减轻他们的愧疚感。
And the other the other thing that I I
还有一点，我
think is particularly pertinent to the
认为和
experience you've had is um so many
你的经历特别相关，那就是很多
small business owners will come up to me
小企业主会来跟我
and say that they are
说，他们
they won't say it like this but what
不会这么说，但
they're describing is that they're a
他们的意思是，他们是……
&gt;&gt; They're at maybe I don't know a million
他们遇到了自身业务的瓶颈。他们的营收可能只有一百万美元左右
in revenue. I mean most people that come
。我的意思是，大多数
up to me say this exact same thing.
来找我的人都这么说。
They've reached about a million in
他们的总营收达到了一百万美元左右，
revenue in total and they don't know how
但他们不知道如何
to scale beyond their typically like
突破传统的
service based businesses where someone's
服务型业务模式，也就是由一个人为
doing a service for a client. And uh
客户提供服务。那么，
people when you've encountered them in
当你在公司里遇到这些人时，你会对他们说什么呢
your your company?
？
&gt;&gt; Welcome to being an entrepreneur. This
欢迎来到创业的世界。
is not a unique set of challenges. This
这并非什么独特的挑战，而是
is an expected set of challenges. The
意料之中的挑战。
statistics show that the challenges that
统计数据显示，
business owners face at that break point
企业主在转型过程中面临的挑战，就是如何将
of taking what they are doing that is
他们行之有效的方法
working and transitioning that to having
转化为需要
other people help them is part of the
其他人协助的工作，这是整个
process. And so there is nothing wrong
过程的一部分。所以，
with this business owner. It's just that
这些企业主本身并没有错。只是
they don't technically know how to train
他们不知道如何有效地培训
somebody to do what they do well that
他人来做好他们所做的工作，
then allows the business owner to focus
从而使他们能够专注
on the business owner's primary role.
于自己的主要职责。
And that primary role should be to
而这个主要职责应该是
generate revenue. It shouldn't be the
创造收入，而不是让牙医整天待在
dentist being in the person's mouth. You
病人嘴里。你
cannot have 12 dental clinics and still
不可能同时管理12个牙医。 诊所里，你仍然要
be the person that is helping the person
帮助病人使用
floss and making sure that they are
牙线，确保他们正确使用
flossing. Right? Mostly hygienists help
牙线。对吧？大多数情况下，牙科保健员会协助
dentists with that. But you have to get
牙医完成这项工作。但你必须跳出日常运营的局限，专注于
operations of your business. And those
业务规模的拓展。而这些
are just skills that you don't currently
正是你目前所
have.
缺乏的技能。
&gt;&gt; And what is that skill? What is the core
那么，这项技能是什么？核心技能是什么
skill there? It's a tactical skill. And
？它是一种策略性技能。
the skill is opening up their calendar,
这项技能就是打开他们的日程表，
looking at what they do every single
审视他们每天的工作内容
day, duplicating through process
，并通过流程创建来复制那些让他们觉得自己
makes them a special snowflake in their
与众不同的做法
mind. Because every business owner
。因为每个企业主都
thinks that they are the only person
认为自己是唯一能
that can talk to their customer. They're
与客户沟通的人，是
the only person that their clients will
唯一客户会
listen to. Nobody is ever going to be
听取意见的人。他们认为没有人能像自己
able to service their patient like them.
一样服务好病人。他们就是
That's what they think. And so they
这么想的。所以，他们
create those conditions instead of
创造了这种局面，而不是
saying, "No, I'm going to objectively
说：“不，我要客观地
look at where I spend my time. And out
审视一下我的时间都花在了哪里。” 在
of all of the things that I do across a
我
50-hour work week, there are specific
每周50小时的工作时间里，有些
things that are not the highest value
事情对我来说价值不高
for me to continue to do, but I would
，但我却
have to train somebody how to do that
需要培训别人才能
thing flawlessly." It is not about
完美地完成它们。问题不在于
hiring somebody who's going to know how
雇佣一个会
to do that thing. That's where they fail
做这些事的人。他们失败的地方就在于此，
and then they lose confidence because
然后他们就失去了信心，因为
they think some magical unicorn employee
他们以为会有一个神奇的独角兽员工突然
is just going to come into their lives
出现，把
and take this thing that only know they
他们唯一擅长的事情变成现实
do it. Of course, they can't. So, it's
。当然，他们做不到。所以，
this reinforcing thought that they have
他们总是固执己见，而不是去梳理思路，明确哪些
parts of the business that I want to
业务环节需要从
remove off of my plate so that in 3
我的工作中移除，以便在
months from now, I do not touch these
三个月后完全摆脱这些
processes. In order to do that, I'm
流程。为了做到这一点，我打算
going to document what I do. Ideally
记录我的工作内容。理想情况下，我会
using a framework like vision,
使用“愿景、
commitment, execution so that it doesn't
承诺、执行”这样的框架，这样
just get reduced down to steps, but so
不仅能将工作简化为步骤，还能让
that team members can understand the why
团队成员理解
behind it, what the organization is
背后的原因，了解组织的
committed to, what the team member needs
承诺，以及…… 团队成员需要
to commit back to, and then actually
重新确认并实际
execute on whatever that process is. And
执行流程。与其
instead of just handing that person
只是
those items in an onboarding and maybe
在入职培训中把这些内容交给他们，然后就
never checking it again, you're going to
置之不理，不如
go through a four-step process. First,
采用四步流程。首先，
you're going to tell the person what
你要告诉他们应
they're supposed to do, aka the process.
该做什么，也就是流程。
Ideally, then you show them what they're
理想情况下，最好能演示给他们看，让
supposed to do so that they can see how
他们明白这些内容
this applies in real life. It's not just
在实际工作中是如何应用的。这不仅仅是
something on a document. Then you're
纸上谈兵。然后，让他们动手
going to let them do that thing. And you
实践。同时，你要
are going to coach them and provide them
指导他们，并就他们的实践提供
feedback on doing that thing. So when
反馈。这样，当
you can see that you've properly trained
你意识到已经对某人进行了有效的培训，
somebody and you've switched your
并且转变了以往认为
mindset from just assuming that adults
成年人
learn the same way that we used to learn
学习方式和
when we were children, which is just by
我们小时候一样（即通过
picking it up and figuring it out.
摸索和理解）的思维模式后，
You're going to give them a full
你就会明白应该为他们提供完整的
structure, tell me, show me, let me
框架，告诉他们流程，演示给他们看，并指导
that they need to be onboarded with. And
他们掌握入职培训中最重要的一些内容。
then you are going to actually measure
最后，你要评估
that they're able to do those things in
他们是否能够完成这些任务。
the way that you were able to do that so
就像你之前那样，你能够妥善
handled. And then you just do that over
处理公司内部的那个角色。然后你就一遍又一遍地重复这个过程
and over and over again.
。
&gt;&gt; So often when people are having this
所以，当人们
conversation with me about this, they
和我谈论这件事时，他们经常会
say, "Oh, I tried that and I brought
说：“哦，我试过了，我找了
someone in and they [__] up and and so
个人来做，结果搞砸了，所以，是的，
yeah, I'm not I'm just going to do it
我不做了，我还是
myself." That's like the rebuttal that I
自己来吧。” 这就是我
always get. It's always people saying,
总是听到的反驳。人们总是说：
"Well, I tried that. I trusted someone.
“嗯，我试过了。” 我信任了某人。
They [__] me over. So that doesn't
他们坑了我。 所以这
work."
行不通。”
&gt;&gt; What responsibility can they take in the
他们在面试过程中能承担什么责任
interview process? What responsibility
？
can they take in the onboarding process?
他们在入职过程中能承担什么责任？
Did they actually show that person what
他们真的向应聘者演示过应
they were supposed to do? Did they
该做什么吗？他们
ensure that the person knew what to do?
确保应聘者知道该做什么吗？
&gt;&gt; Do you think most people are bad at
你认为大多数人都不擅长
hiring?
招聘吗？
&gt;&gt; Of course they are. People are terrible
当然不。人们
at hiring.
在招聘方面很糟糕。他们
&gt;&gt; Where do they go wrong? Like what are
错在哪里？是什么
the biases that they that end up
偏见最终
consuming that process that make them
影响了招聘流程，导致他们
make a bad decision?
做出错误的决定？
&gt;&gt; I don't think they really understand
我认为他们并不真正了解他们
what the work is that they're trying to
想让应聘者做的工作是什么
get that person to do. So they Google a
。所以他们会在谷歌上搜索
job description or they chat GPT or use
职位描述，或者使用Google Play搜索，或者用
Grock to put a job description that
Grock等工具来编写职位描述，而这些描述
isn't actually connected to the real
实际上与该
outcomes in the role. I can imagine if
职位的实际工作成果无关。我可以想象，如果
you posted for a marketing position
你在
inside your business. For you, marketing
公司内部招聘市场营销人员。对你来说，市场营销
looks like lots of different things.
涵盖很多不同的方面。
Yeah. For the average business owner,
是的。但对于普通的企业主来说，
I'm just going to I need somebody to
我可能只是需要有人
help me with marketing.
帮我做市场营销。
&gt;&gt; They don't even know what they're hiring
他们甚至不知道自己在招聘什么
for. Yeah.
。是的。不。
&gt;&gt; No. So then the person comes in with a
所以，应聘者带着一些
certain set of experiences and they are
特定的经验来应聘，而招聘方会
going to drive based off of their
根据这些经验来做决定。 他们的
experiences whatever they think the
经历，无论他们认为自己
outcomes are for their role inside that
在公司里扮演的角色会带来怎样的结果，都取决于他们的个人体验，
business because the owner never took
因为老板从未承担起
the responsibility to say this is how
责任，明确表示将如何
I'm going to objectively measure. Was
客观地衡量业绩。
this person successful based off of the
这个人成功与否，仅仅因为
fact that the marketing that we do for
我们为
our plumbing business that's doing
一家年
$800,000 of revenue is actually email
收入80万美元的管道公司所做的营销实际上是电子邮件
marketing?
营销？
&gt;&gt; So, what if I don't know the right type
那么，如果我不懂正确的营销方式怎么办
of marketing? Cuz I'm a plumber. I don't
？因为我只是个水管工，我
know about [__] marketing. So, I'm
对营销一窍不通。所以，如果
going to be very easily duped by someone
有人
that tells me that they know marketing.
自称懂营销，我很容易被骗。
What do I do to
我该如何
minimize the probability of me being
降低
duped?
被骗的概率？
Well, the good news is if you are a
好消息是，如果你现在是一名
plumber currently and you're doing,
水管工，
let's say, $800,000 of revenue, you
假设你的年收入是80万美元，那么你已经
figured out marketing for $800,000 of
掌握了80万美元
revenue. So, the first thing in order to
收入的营销方法。因此，为了
not be duped would be ensuring that the
避免被骗，首先要确保你招
person that you're bringing on can at
进来的人至少能
least do what you are doing and they can
做到你正在做的事情，并且能够
duplicate what you are doing. Now, once
复制你正在做的事情。一旦
they've demonstrated to you that they
他们向你展示了这一点，你就可以开始行动了。 他们
can take on those tasks for that
能够承担那
800,000, they are competent. They
80万美元的业绩任务，他们胜任。他们
understand the business. They understand
了解业务，也了解
who your customer is because you forced
你的客户群体，因为你让
them to. because you documented what you
他们了解了。因为你记录了你如何
did did to get the first 800 and maybe
获得最初的800个客户，甚至可能还有
that's even referrals. Great. What is
推荐。太好了。
your referral process and how then once
你的推荐流程是什么？一旦
they've been able to master what you
他们掌握了你
created a model for? I like to call this
创建的模式，又该如何推广？我喜欢称之为“
the four M's. Model, mimic, master,
4M”：建模（Model）、模仿（Mimic）、掌握（Master）、
multiply. The business owner can first
倍增（Multiply）。企业主可以先
create the model of what they are doing
创建一个模型，展示他们
today that's generating the $800,000 of
目前在管道业务中创造80万美元
revenue in their plumbing business. I
收入的方式。
take a model. I have the model. This is
我有一个模型，比如
inside our business. Then I move into
我们公司内部的电子邮件营销模式。然后，我会
seeing if they can mimic what is the
观察他们是否能够模仿其中的
behavior to then move into mastering it.
行为，并最终掌握它。
And once somebody is at mastering
一旦有人掌握了管道
something inside a plumbing business for
业务中
$800,000 a year that it's generating,
每年创造80万美元收入的某种方法，
they can then start to tweak and add
他们就可以开始进行调整和添加，
things and and maybe we're going to also
或许我们还会
try one other thing. We're going to try
尝试其他方法。 我们将尝试
Instagram marketing because we know that
Instagram营销，因为我们知道
our plumbing clients are on Instagram
我们的管道客户都在使用Instagram，
and we're going to have this strategy
而且我们也会制定相应的策略
here. So now I'm going to be able to add
。现在我可以在此基础上进行补充
to that. At which point when a team
。当团队
member can go through those first three
成员能够完成建模、
M's, model, mimic, master, then they're
模仿和精通这三个步骤（M）时，他们就能
in a position to multiply their role.
拓展自己的角色。
Because if they really did master
因为如果他们真的精通了
something, the results would show that
某项技能，结果就会
to indicate that the business is ready
表明公司已经准备好在
coordinator underneath the marketing
营销经理之下增设一名营销协调员，
manager that can then go through those
负责完成这
first three steps of the process. while
三个步骤。而
the team member who was once responsible
之前负责
for those things is no longer doing
这些工作的团队成员不再需要亲自执行
those things but is being additive to
这些任务，而是为公司
additional types of marketing inside
内部其他类型的营销活动做出贡献
that business. The the other thing that
。
I often wonder is if people aim too low
我经常思考的另一点是，如果人们
with talent, especially like earlier
对人才的要求过低，尤其是像早期
stage founders, they tend they tend
创业者这样的人，他们往往会缺乏
there tends to be a bit of insecurity
安全感，
there and they don't want
不希望
someone to come in and tell them what to
有人来告诉他们在
do in a particular domain
某个特定领域该怎么做。
&gt;&gt; because I think the further I've got in
因为我认为，随着我
my career, the more I've sought out
职业生涯的深入，我越来越倾向于寻找比我
smarter than me and I see that as the
聪明得多的人。 比我更了解我，我认为这才是
game. But in the early innings of my
游戏规则。但在我
career, I think I was
职业生涯的早期，我
hiring people I could manage.
雇佣的都是我可以管理的人。
Do you think you weren't as successful
你觉得
when you were hiring people you could
当你雇佣那些你可以完全管理的人时，你的成功率会降低吗
manage
？
&gt;&gt; Because now you're able to bring on
因为现在你可以招募
talent to help you bring on whole new
人才来帮助你开辟全新的
lines of revenue, whole new
收入来源、全新的
partnerships, business opportunities,
合作伙伴关系、商业机会，并
manage those things.
管理好这些。
&gt;&gt; Yeah. In the early innings of my career,
是的。在我职业生涯的早期，
I was particularly aiming at young
我特别关注和
people that were like my age or younger
我年龄相仿或更年轻的年轻人，
cuz I was what I was what 20. So, I'm
因为我当时才20岁。所以我
like, how how the hell am I going to
就想，我怎么可能
bring in a 45-year-old that's been doing
招到一个45岁、从业
this for 25 years and get and and be
25年的人，然后
able to tell them anything, which is
还能对他们指手画脚呢？这就是我当时
what which was the fault in my thinking
想法的错误之处，
cuz I thought my job was to tell them
因为我以为我的工作是告诉他们
what to do and to give them the vision
该做什么，给他们愿景。
and but actually as I I think got more
但实际上，随着我越来越
secure in myself, I realized that the
自信，我意识到
game is the inverse, which is try and
游戏规则恰恰相反，那就是要努力
find truly exceptional people that know
寻找真正杰出的人才，他们知道
things I don't know and create the
我不知道的事情，并创造
conditions where their knowledge is adds
条件让他们能够…… 他们的知识丰富了
this organization.
我们组织的集体智慧，
And actually that's what we need. We
而这正是我们所需要的。我们
need new thinking, new experiences.
需要新的思维，新的经验。
&gt;&gt; I think that's important once you reach
我认为，一旦
$30 million of revenue. But until you as
营收达到3000万美元，这一点就显得尤为重要。但是，作为创始人，除非你
can generate something that you can
能创造出一些
prove works and you can replicate what
行之有效且可以复制的成功模式
works, you open yourself up to
，否则你将面临
significant risk. And the stats show it.
巨大的风险。统计数据也证实了这一点：
the the majority of businesses, 97% of
97%的
businesses fail within 10 years. So by
企业会在10年内倒闭。所以，如果你仅仅
trusting or thinking that you're going
相信或认为你会
to bring on somebody who's smarter than
招来一个比你更聪明的人
you, you're not actually taking on your
，实际上你并没有真正承担起自己的
role to say this is what I want to
责任，去阐述“这就是我想
build. This is what I've built so far.
打造的东西，这就是我目前为止的成果”。
before you will be additive to this
在你加入这个
environment, I need to make sure that
团队之前，我需要确保
what we have built so far, the $800,000
我们目前已经取得的成就——80万美元
of revenue, the $2 million of revenue,
、200万美元、1000万
the $10 million of revenue, I need to
美元的营收——
first make sure that you can do that.
你能够做到。
&gt;&gt; Because if you can't do that, and we
因为如果你做不到，如果我们
can't duplicate what we're already doing
无法复制我们目前行之有效的模式，那么
that works well, we don't know what is
我们…… 不知道引入什么是
the right idea to bring in because there
正确的想法，因为你对这家
makes this business run today. And the
公司目前的运营模式缺乏核心理解。而
last thing that you want to do is bring
你最不想做的就是
on a leader. Let's say your business is
引进一位领导者。假设你的公司年
doing $10 million of revenue and you
收入1000万美元，你
think that there's somebody out there
认为外面有个人
that is smarter than you who's going to
比你更聪明，能够
entirely change your sales process.
彻底改变你的销售流程。
Maybe you weren't the best salesperson.
也许你并不是最优秀的销售人员。
You hired a salesperson on very early.
你很早就招了一位销售人员。
They've tapped out in their ability to
他已经无法再
add additional salespeople and really
增加销售人员，也无法真正
properly run a sales team. Well, as soon
有效地管理销售团队。那么，
as that's happened and you're going to
一旦这种情况发生，当你打算
bring on this external person, it would
引进这位外部人员时，
be great if they could add $20 million
如果他能带来2000万美元
of revenue. But if it's through some
的收入，那当然很好。但如果他带来的是
different product and different service
不同的产品、不同的服务、
and different way that disrupts what got
不同的方式，颠覆了
you to 10 million, you're not at 10
你取得1000万美元收入的模式，那么你的收入就不再是1000
million any longer. You're at 8 million
万美元了。你可能只有800万美元
or 7 million. And there's real slipbacks
或700万美元。而且，收入确实会下滑
that happen. And to me, that's more of
。在我看来，这才是更
the reality that I see, which is the
现实的情况，收入
slipback because the business owner
下滑是因为…… 企业主对
of the business to decide how the
企业的核心业务了解不足，无法决定
business is run, what the core offer is
企业的运营方式和核心产品，也就没有足够的
to have the confidence to then bring on
信心引进那些能为企业增添价值、
people who are additive that can't break
不会破坏
the business.
企业发展的人才。
So you think we you should approach with
因此，你认为应该
caution because there's risk associated
谨慎行事，因为引进
with on boarding people that might be
人才存在风险，这些人可能
expensive and um
成本高昂，而且……嗯，他们可能
know too much about I guess be I guess
了解太多。我想，
it goes back to being duped be able to
这又回到了被人欺骗的
learn the reasons why. This doesn't have
问题上。如果你不完全理解他们所说的话和他们所知道的，他们就无法欺骗你。如果你真的愿意效仿你目前的做法，而他们也愿意谦虚地融入你的环境并学习背后的原因，那么这个过程并不需要
to take years. This can take a handful
几年，可能只需要
of months. I'm not talking about like
几个月。我说的不是要
stifling innovation for quarters and
扼杀创新几个季度
quarters or years and years to make sure
甚至几年，确保
that they like really are indoctrinated
他们真正接受
with the way that the organization
组织的
works. Absolutely not. That wouldn't
运作方式。绝对不行，那样行不通
work. The way you have to do it is
。正确的做法是
quickly assessing that they understand
迅速评估他们是否理解。 了解
the way the things work inside your
你
current business. We just recently
现有业务的运作方式。我们最近刚
brought on a new seauite um within the
招了一位新的高管，
first handful of weeks. I can tell that
短短几周内，我就能看出
he's picking up on what our core
他正在了解我们核心
business has does. And if I didn't think
业务的运作方式。如果我不
that, it would be hard for me to trust
这么认为，我就很难相信
some of his recommendations because I
他的一些建议，因为我
this year who had all these fanciful
今年早些时候也招了一位高管，他有很多天马行空的
ideas and this, you know, the the big
想法，你知道，都是些
names and you think that they're going
大人物，你以为他们会
to bring on all these things, but they
带来各种各样的东西，但他们
can't actually contextualize what their
实际上无法将自己的
experience is to the core business
经验与核心业务联系起来，
because they don't understand the core
因为他们不了解核心
business. And then it ends up
业务。最终，这导致
they're responsible for working with.
他们负责的团队成员感到被排斥。
And I have seen more often than not that
我经常看到，在
founder getting the necessary skills
创始人没有掌握必要技能的情况下过早信任他，最终的结果往往是
ends up in the luck scenario instead of
运气使然，而不是
this was a strategy because I knew and
策略使然。因为我了解并
had certainty about what was going on
确信正在发生的事情，
and I'm good with what my four walls
我对我的工作环境很满意
are. This is what you are going to
。这就是你要
bring. That is incredibly additive to
带来的。这对核心业务来说是非常有益的
that core business. But that rigor and
。但严谨性和
that discipline has to be there from the
纪律性同样重要。
founder first.
首先，创始人必须具备这样的素质。
&gt;&gt; It's interesting. Yeah, it's really
这很有意思。是的，真的很
interesting. And I think part of my bias
有意思。我觉得我的偏见部分原因
is because I've been there before. I
是因为我以前有过类似的经历。
would never start a new business now
现在，如果我不追求顶尖人才，我绝不会再创办新公司。
talent. But that's actually because I'm
但实际上，这是因为我
harder to dup now. So if you have to pay
现在更难被骗了。所以，比如，如果你要给
someone a huge salary for example and
某人支付巨额薪水和丰厚的福利，
&gt;&gt; I'm better able to assess whether they
我更能评估他们是否
are worth it and what their ROI is going
物有所值，以及他们的投资回报率是多少。这与
to be versus the start of my career
我职业生涯初期截然不同，那时我
where hiring someone on and taking such
雇佣员工，承担如此
a big risk on someone I didn't have
大的风险，却没有
enough data to understand if I was being
足够的数据来判断自己是否
duped or not. So it was a lot of faith
被骗了。所以，当时我完全是出于
and trust and well they worked at this
信任，觉得“他们在一家
incredible company so they must be good
很棒的公司工作，所以他们肯定很优秀”
backfire as well. um you talk about
。我也见过这种做法完全适得其反的例子。你在2024年
in a video that you made uh in December
12月发布的一个视频中谈到了成为百万富翁的十个
in 24 and there are a couple of things
步骤，
that I wanted to to pull out here. So
我想在这里提几点。
you outline out outline this 10-step
你在视频中概述了成为百万富翁的十个步骤。
a year and one of them is researching
一年的时间，其中一项任务是研究
what jobs millionaires have.
百万富翁们都从事哪些工作。
Then rate your interest and skills in
然后评估你对每项工作的兴趣和技能，
each and pick one to master.
并选择一项来精通。
The other one is cut out friends who
另一项任务是远离那些
drain energy or don't stop your goals.
消耗你精力或阻碍你实现目标的朋友。
your field through podcast, videos, and
通过播客、视频和书籍，学习你所在领域最成功的10个人
books.
。
Use every moment to build skills. Follow
利用每一刻来提升技能。
only millionaires on social media and
在社交媒体上只关注百万富翁，并
eliminate all distractions such as
消除所有干扰，例如
Netflix and doom scrolling.
Netflix和刷社交媒体。
Be willing to invest and go into debt
要有投资和负债的意愿，
as without investment knowledge, you
因为缺乏投资知识，你
will stay broke.
将一直贫穷。
Attend events with successful people.
参加成功人士的活动。
Research you'll be attending. Master
事先做好功课，了解你要参加的活动。
your team members daily.
每天都要精通如何推销自己、你的客户和你的团队成员。
On this point of selling, is there
关于销售，关于
anything on this subject of how to be a
如何成为一名
great salesperson that we haven't talked
优秀的销售人员，还有什么我们没谈到但
about that you think is important?
你认为重要的方面吗？
Whether it's selling yourself or selling
无论是推销自己、推销你的
your ideas or selling your business or
想法、推销你的事业，还是
&gt;&gt; one of my favorite quotes from Grant
我最喜欢的格兰特·卡多内（Grant Cardone）的一句名言
Cardone, to the extent you are sold, you
：你被说服的程度决定了你
will sell.
推销的程度。
&gt;&gt; Oh, okay. So to the extent in which you
哦，好的。所以，你
believe something is the extent you'll
相信某件事的程度决定了你
be able to make others believe in the
让别人相信这
thing.
件事的程度。
&gt;&gt; Mhm. So if you're not sold on yourself,
嗯。 所以，如果你对自己、
on your business idea, on the product
自己的商业理念、
that you're selling for the company that
你为公司销售的产品、以及
you work for, on getting another
让其他
department to work crossunctionally with
部门与你跨部门合作都不满意
you, if you aren't really sold on that,
，如果你对这些都不真正有信心，
you will not sell. But I think it goes a
你就卖不出去。但我认为问题往往比
layer deeper than that often times
这更深层次，
because
因为人们很
it's easy to look at I'm not selling the
容易只看到自己没能把
product inside my business. Maybe I'm a
产品卖出去。也许我是个
team member. I'm in sales and I'm not
销售团队成员，
hitting my quota this month of cars that
这个月没完成我的汽车销售指标
I'm supposed to sell. And I'm like,
。然后我就会想，
well, like I don't really feel good
嗯，我卖车这件事让我感觉很不好
about the fact that I sell cars. Like I
。
this car is a piece of crap. Of course,
这车简直就是个垃圾。当然，
I'm not selling the car. And you can get
我卖不出去。你可以对这
very critical of the thing and
件事进行各种批判，并为
rationalize why you are not good at
自己不擅长
sales. But if you really do take a step
销售找理由。但如果你真的冷静
back, why did you choose to sell cars in
下来想想，你当初为什么选择卖车
the first place? Why is that the thing
？为什么
that you said, I'm going to spend my
你决定把
time and energy being sold on? You could
时间和精力花在推销这件事上？你本来可以
have chosen lots of other opportunities.
选择很多其他的机会。
firm that you wanted to work at instead
你当初一心想去那家公关公司，而
not confronting the PR rejection that
不是接受你找到的销售工作，也没有正视被公关公司拒绝的事实，结果就陷入了
you got landed you in this place where
这种进退两难的境地：你对工作提不起兴趣，开始
you're unsold and then you're critical
挑剔工作
of your environment and you're critical
环境和
of the product and then you think you're
产品，然后觉得自己
not good at sales when really you just
不擅长销售。其实，你只
needed to go back to that thing that you
需要回到当初真正让你心动的那件事，
were actually sold on because you sold
因为是你
yourself on why you thought for you that
自己说服了自己，认为那
was your opportunity. then you just
是你的机会。结果你
missed the target and instead of being
错过了目标，与其
unreasonable about the target, you
对目标不切实际，不如
became reasonable and started selling
理性地去推销
something you didn't believe in and then
自己都不相信的东西，然后
you think that you're not good at sales.
你又觉得自己不擅长销售。
And so the reasonleness
所以，你内心对理想工作的理性追求，正是
is actually why I find that salespeople
我发现销售人员
can't sell. It's not about their
无法成功销售的原因。这与他们的
inherent skills. If I can get them sold
天赋无关。如果我能让他们
on the product, of course I'm going to
相信产品，我当然能让
get them sold on the product. I help
他们相信。我帮助
business owners across the country get
全国各地的企业主
sold on getting their team members to
让他们的团队成员相信
sell roofs. I believe that somebody
销售屋顶的重要性。我相信，有人
knocking on the door and selling roofs
上门推销屋顶
is the most important thing for that
才是最重要的。 对于我的
team member. I am sold on the fact that
团队成员来说，我确信
they're working for a roofer who cares
他们正在为一位真正关心他们的屋顶公司工作
about them. So, I'm like, "Hell yeah,
。所以，我当时就想：“好啊，
let's get on the roof." I've was on a
咱们上屋顶吧！”
roof about a month ago and then was on
大约一个月前我上过一个屋顶，
another roof two months ago cuz I
两个月前又上过另一个，因为我
literally helped these business owners
确实在帮助这些企业主
train their sales team members to sell
培训他们的销售团队成员如何销售
roofs. And these sales team members
屋顶。这些销售团队成员
aren't naturally interested in roofs.
并非天生就对屋顶感兴趣。
They didn't wake up one day and thinking
他们不是某天醒来突然想：
like, "My life's dream is to sell a
“我的人生梦想就是卖
roof." But what are they sold on?
屋顶。”但他们究竟被什么吸引呢？
They're sold on the opportunity to
他们被
potentially join this roofing company to
加入这家屋顶公司的机会所吸引，
three locations, five locations because
因为
the business owner has created that
企业主
vision for them and the salesperson can
为他们描绘了这样的愿景，而销售人员可以凭借
sell themselves on the skills that they
自己销售屋顶的技能来推销自己
have to understand how to sell a roof.
。这
Maybe not the sexiest thing, but that's
或许不是最吸引人的事情，但这却是
a stepping stone in order to be a future
成为未来
expansion partner with this business
与这位企业
owner because this opportunity exists.
主共同扩张的垫脚石，因为机会就在那里。
So, how do I sell a roof? If I'm on that
那么，我该如何销售屋顶呢？如果我和
roof with you and you're trying to train
你一起在屋顶上，而你正在培训
me to sell the roof better,
我…… 为了更好地推销屋顶，
&gt;&gt; how what are you saying to me is
你的意思是
&gt;&gt; Well, ideally, you're knocking on the
，理想情况下，你要去敲
door of the homeowner.
房主的门。
&gt;&gt; Okay. I knock on the door.
好的，我敲门，
&gt;&gt; You knock on the door.
你也敲门。
&gt;&gt; Yeah.
是的。
&gt;&gt; And you go through if there was a storm.
然后，如果附近有暴风雨，你就可以进去查看。
There's all sorts of ways that you can
有很多方法可以
sell roofs, but let's say that there was
推销屋顶，但假设
a storm nearby or recently that hit that
附近或最近有暴风雨袭击了该
area and you could go the easier route,
地区，你可以选择更简单的途径，
which is going through insurance because
即通过保险，因为
that roof is completely then paid for.
保险会全额赔付。
But then you'd need to go up on the roof
但这样一来，你就需要爬上屋顶
and or use a drone to look at the real
，或者使用无人机查看实际的
damage because that in and of itself is
损坏情况，因为这本身就是
a sales skill. Somebody going up and
一种销售技巧。有人上去
pointing out the problem that that
指出
person has that they do not know in that
房主当时没有意识到的问题，
moment that they have helps the person
这能帮助房主
feel confident in selling that roof. So,
更有信心推销屋顶。所以，亲自上
go walk the roof or to fly a drone over
屋顶查看损坏情况，或者用无人机飞过
that roof to see the damage as it is a
屋顶查看损坏情况，既是
selling mechanism for the salesperson
销售人员的销售技巧，也是整个流程的一部分，
because you're not just selling somebody
因为你不是在向一个不需要屋顶的人推销屋顶，
actually have a problem. And then you
而是在帮助他们解决实际问题。 你
would educate that sales individual on
需要向销售人员讲解屋顶问题
the damage that that can do long term,
可能造成的长期损害，以及
the value loss of that property. And if
房产价值的损失。如果
you can sell the salesperson on why that
你能让销售人员明白，
homeowner deserves to know that their
房主应该知道他们的
roof has something that insurance could
屋顶存在保险可以赔付的问题，而且可以在
within a handful of weeks that doesn't
几周内修好，不会
erode the biggest investment that that
损害他们一生中最大的投资——
their home. All of a sudden, I have an
房子，那么突然之间，我就会拥有
army of salespeople who are interested
一大批对销售屋顶服务感兴趣的销售人员，
in selling roofs because they're sold
因为他们
not just on the fact that it's a roof,
不仅被屋顶本身吸引，
but the impact that that work makes on
更被这项工作对客户的影响所打动，
ideally the opportunity that they have
理想情况下，他们还会被
inside that company to be freaking great
公司提供的机会所吸引，成为一名出色的
at selling roofs.
屋顶销售专家。
&gt;&gt; So, you you pointed out the problem that
所以，
they have. You've then assigned a cost
你指出了他们面临的
to that problem, how much it's going to
问题，然后评估了这个问题的成本，包括
cost them over the long term or short
长期和
term, and then you posed the solution,
短期成本，最后提出了解决方案——
which is to get the roof repaired. And I
维修屋顶。我
guess you're trying to frame the
想，你是在努力让
solution relative to the cost so that
解决方案与成本挂钩，确保
the solution is not bigger or more
解决方案不会
costly than the the cost of having a bad
比成本更高。 就像
roof.
屋顶破旧一样。
Earlier on, you mentioned um this this
之前你提到过一个
phrase which I've not heard before and
我以前没听过的说法，就在
it was just before we started recording
我们开始录音之前，
you talked about a woman's wealth
你谈到了女性财富
transfer.
转移。
&gt;&gt; And when I asked you what was front of
当我问你
mind for you at the moment, you
当时最关心的是什么时，你
referenced that you were thinking a lot
说你一直在思考
about the women's wealth transfer. What
女性财富转移的问题。
is this?
这是什么？
&gt;&gt; The women's wealth transfer. between
女性财富转移。根据美国的数据，从
2025 and 2030 looks like just these are
2025年到2030年，
hands of women right now and between now
女性手中目前拥有10万亿美元的财富，而从现在到
and 2030 that number is going to go up
2030年，这个数字将上升
to $30 trillion.
到30万亿美元。
So this wealth is going to balloon. And
所以，这笔财富将会暴增。
when you think about the implications of
当你思考
how this wealth transfer happens, it's
这种财富转移的影响时，你会发现，这
not just cash that is given to women all
不仅仅是因为女性收入
more money. There's a transition because
增加而突然获得现金。这其中存在着一种过渡，因为
partners. A man and a woman, there's
伴侣的预期寿命存在差异。平均而言，
&gt;&gt; men are going to die first.
男性会先于女性去世。是的，
&gt;&gt; Yep. And it's about five and a half, six
大约是五年半到
years. So women are left with assets,
六年。所以，女性会留下资产，而
not cash, like homes, businesses,
不是…… 现金，就像房产、企业、投资
portfolios, investments, bank accounts
组合、投资、银行账户一样，
that often times they were left out of
她们往往被排除在
the conversation with the financial
与财务
adviser. And they don't actually know
顾问的对话之外。她们实际上不知道
how to operationalize, how to manage
如何运作、如何管理这些资产，
because up until as recent as 50 years
因为直到50年前
ago, women weren't even allowed to open
，女性甚至不允许在
bank accounts without their husband or
没有丈夫或父亲的陪同下开设银行账户，
their father until that passed in the
直到
80s. And so the wealth is actually
80年代才有所改变。因此，财富实际上正在
moving towards women. But women today
向女性转移。但如今，
feel less financially able due to
由于内容创作，女性感觉自己的财务能力有所下降
content creation. There was recent study
。
done by a company called Elvest where
一家名为Elvest的公司最近进行了一项研究，
they analyze the amount of manifestation
分析了
content on the internet created by women
互联网上女性
creators. There's 12 times as much
创作者创作的显化类内容的数量。结果显示，
manifestation content from women
女性创作者的显化类内容数量
creators as there is investing and
是投资和
equity content. Or 70% of women feel
股权类内容的12倍。或者说，70%的女性
information after consuming the content
在阅读这些内容后感到财务信息更加难以应对，
because it's a tip or trick or hack that
因为这些内容分享的是一些技巧、窍门或秘诀，而
is being shared instead of a real system
不是一个真正的系统
and process for how do they take
和流程，教她们如何将
something and systematize or
资产系统化或
operationalize this business that has
运作化，从而管理好拥有
equity. But then there's trucks maybe
股权的业务。此外，
that they're inheriting. Then there's
她们可能还要继承卡车，还要承担
debt on this business. And it's just a
企业的债务。 这完全是一个
brand new conversation. And as women get
全新的话题。随着女性
more financially literate, as they get
金融素养的提高，以及她们获得
more financial opportunities, there have
更多经济机会，
to be more ways for them to be in these
她们必须有更多途径参与到这些
conversations. They have there have to
对话中来。她们必须
be more ways for them to understand how
有更多途径去理解如何
to navigate what opportunities didn't
把握那些在
recent as 20, 30 years ago. And so I'm
二三十年前甚至更久远之前都不存在的机会。所以我
passionate about this because I see this
对此充满热情，因为 我看到了一个
incredible time where
不可思议的时代，
I help people every day understand how
我每天都在帮助人们了解如何
to grow businesses and be competent in
发展业务，如何在商业领域取得成功
businesses. So as the total wealth
。 因此，在
transfer takes place over the next 20
接下来的 20
years from baby boomers to the next
年里，随着财富从婴儿潮一代转移到下一代
generation, that total wealth transfer
，财富转移总额
is about $124 trillion.
约为 124 万亿美元。
How do I equip women to feel confident
我该如何帮助女性
with the decisions that they're making,
对自己做出的决定充满信心，而
to not just fire their financial
不是像
advisor, which 70% of them do after
70% 的女性在
their spouse dies within the first year,
配偶去世后的第一年内那样解雇她们的财务顾问，
and actually know before this
而是在这种灾难性事件发生之前，真正了解如何
control the money, how they feel
控制金钱，如何
confident with the money. So that once
对金钱充满信心。 这样，一旦
they have it, it is not in moments of
他们拥有了这些，就不会在
panic and stress and frustration that
恐慌、压力和沮丧的时刻去
they are having to figure these things
解决这些问题了
out. They already feel like they are
。 他们觉得自己已经
equipped with conversations about what
具备了讨论损益表
is a P&amp;L and how do I understand what's
是什么以及如何了解
happening with my 401k and still some of
我的 401k 账户情况的能力，但其中一些
these concepts are just out of sight,
概念仍然遥不可及，被人们
out of mind and traditionally held by
遗忘，并且传统上由
male roles in a household. So what would
家庭中的男性角色承担。 那么，对于那些缺乏金融知识的
you recommend people do who find
人，您会建议他们怎么做呢
they're they are financially illiterate?
？
You used the word earlier on financial
你之前在谈到金融危机时也用过这个词
crisis.
。
&gt;&gt; Is that dovetailing into the same thing?
这两者之间是否属于同一范畴？
Is that because people is that the
是因为人们缺乏
financial illiteracy point?
金融知识吗？
&gt;&gt; You say financial crisis
你说金融危机，但
&gt;&gt; for me the financial crisis is how few
对我来说，金融危机是指
people are actually making enough money
真正能赚到足够钱
to make ends meet. The financial crisis
维持生计的人太少了。 金融危机
is that there are so many businesses, 35
在于，企业数量如此之多（
million in the US alone, and yet less
仅美国就有 3500 万家），但年
than 200,000 make more than a million
收入超过 100 万
dollars. And if less than 200,000 make a
美元的企业却不到 20 万家。 如果不到 20 万人赚到
million over a million dollars, and the
超过一百万美元，而
average margin of a business is 8.5%,
企业的平均利润率为 8.5%，那么
you just you you're circling the drain
你就会发现，
as to how much money people are actually
人们实际赚到的钱少得可怜
making. It seems like there's so much
。
money because of social media. And there
社交媒体似乎带来了巨额财富。
are team members who work in
有些团队成员在年
organizations that make more than
收入超过
$60,000 a year, but people are actually
6 万美元的组织中工作，但
making less money than I think society
我认为，由于内容创作的普及，人们的实际收入比社会认为的要低
content creation. And so this crisis to
。 因此，在我看来，这场危机
me is has much more to do with how do we
更多的是关于我们如何让
get people skills that they need with
人们掌握他们所需的技能，因为
coming out due to AI in healthcare in
根据人工智能在医疗保健和
genomics.
基因组学领域不断涌现的各种治疗方法，我们的预期寿命看起来将会更长。
&gt;&gt; What do you think is the most important
您认为
financial information the average person
普通人
needs in this regard?
在这方面最需要哪些财务信息？
&gt;&gt; I think the most important financial
我认为最重要的财务
information is actually that money
信息其实是：金钱很
matters. And if money matters, how are
重要。 如果金钱对你来说很重要，那么
you spending your time today, tomorrow,
你今天、明天、后天是如何利用时间来
the next day to get skills and to do
学习技能和做能
things that generate money? And if you
赚钱的事情的呢？ 如果你
can align your time with making more
能把时间花在赚钱上，而
money instead of thinking that it's some
不是认为钱是某种
fixed resource or there is some scarcity
固定资源或稀缺资源
around it, you could actually increase
，你实际上可以提高
the the top line because you can save
收入，因为你可以通过储蓄来达到收支平衡
your way to the bottom, but you get to
，但最终你会达到收支平衡
the bottom. There's no abundance in the
。 底部并不富足
in the bottom. So what are the skills?
。 那么需要哪些技能呢？
Like if I was somebody that was trying
比如，如果我
to earn more money today, I would go on
今天想赚更多钱，我会去
to one of the AI platforms and say this
某个人工智能平台，然后说这
is the set of skills that I have. These
是我拥有的技能。 以上
are the set of interests that I have.
是我感兴趣的领域。
This is the current job that I hold,
这是我目前的工作，
what I do for work, and my goal is to
我从事的工作，我的目标是在
increase my income between now and 12
未来 12 个月内将我的收入增加
months from now by $100,000. what are
10 万美元。
syllabus for each week if I carved out
如果我
two hours a day for me to learn that you
每天抽出两个小时学习，你
could put together for me so that I can
能为我安排一下每周的具体技能和相关课程大纲吗？这样我才能
actually get skills that would
真正掌握能够
demonstrate that I'm able to make more
证明我有能力赚更多
money. And I think that message is
钱的技能。 我认为
missed when people talk about investing
人们在谈论投资
and 401ks.
和 401k 计划时，往往忽略了这一点。
Sure, you can make your 6%, your 8%,
当然，你可以做到 6%、8%、
your 10%. But what can you actually
10%。 但你究竟能
control? And what does every individual
控制什么呢？ 那么，每个人
have the ability to control? their
又能控制什么呢？ 他们的
skills and how they exchange those
技能，以及他们如何用这些
skills for problems that they are
技能来
solving in exchange earning more income
解决问题，从而赚取更多收入，
and then they're able to invest in and
然后他们就能投资并
do all of those other things. But those
做所有其他的事情。 但这些
things are ancilliary. They are not the
都是辅助性的。 它们并不是最重要的
main thing. The main thing is you need
。 最重要的是你要
to get skills. You are going to live
掌握技能。 你会活得更
longer. Wake up, smell the roses. The
久。 醒醒吧，闻闻玫瑰的芬芳。
world is going to be a very long place
世界将是一个非常漫长的地方，
that you are going to inhabit for the
你平均
next potentially hundred years on
可能要在这里生活一百年
average. So let's get comfortable with
。 所以，让我们习惯于
learning more, understanding what our
学习更多知识，了解我们
stops are to learning so that we aren't
学习的障碍是什么，这样，当
scared as the world changes of having to
世界发生变化，我们就不会害怕
acquire new skills. Before the Diary of
获得新技能。 在《
a CEO was what it is today, it was just
CEO日记》成为今天的样子之前，它还只是
an idea. And it started with me, a cheap
一个想法。 这一切都始于我、一个廉价的
plug-in microphone, and my Mac right
外接麦克风和我的Mac电脑
here. And I have to say when I first had
。 我必须说，当我最初萌生写
the idea for the diary of a CEO, my
CEO日记的想法时，我的
thinking was that the world might want
想法是，世界可能想
to see into the diaries of some of the
看看一些身居高位、做着有趣事情的
most interesting, successful people
最有趣、最成功的人的日记
interesting things. So after recording
。 所以，在被窝里录完
that first episode under my duvet, I sat
第一集之后，我
on my Mac, which is from our sponsor
坐在赞助商苹果公司提供的Mac电脑前，
Apple, and spent hours editing and
花了几个小时进行编辑，
eventually uploaded it. And honestly, I
最终上传了节目。 说实话，我当时
thought that would probably be it. But a
觉得事情大概就是这样了。 但
couple of my friends said they enjoyed
我的几个朋友说他们很喜欢
it, so I kept on recording. And over
，所以我继续录制了下去。 随着
time, the microphone has changed and we
时间的推移，麦克风也发生了变化，我们
now have this incredible setup here. The
现在拥有了这套令人难以置信的设备。 唯一没变的
thing that has stayed the same is I'm
是，我
still using the Mac. Even today, my
还在使用Mac电脑。 直到今天，
entire team across our studio still uses
我们工作室的整个团队仍然在使用
the Mac. Our first few episodes maybe
Mac电脑。 我们最初几期节目可能
had tens of people listening, but now
只有几十个人听，但现在
tens of millions of people tune in all
全世界有数千万人收听
over the world, which is still
，这对
absolutely crazy to me. So, if there is
我来说仍然非常不可思议。 所以，如果
an idea that keeps tapping you on the
你脑海中一直萦绕着一个想法
shoulder, this is your sign to start.
，那就是你应该开始行动的信号了。
Your great ideas start on Mac. And you
你的伟大创意始于Mac。 您
can find out more at apple.com/mac.
可以在 apple.com/mac 上了解更多信息。
I did something at 24 years old that has
我在24岁时做了一件
had a profound impact on my life. I set
对我的人生影响深远的事情。 我给
myself the challenge of posting every
自己设定了挑战，
single day on my social media channels.
每天都要在我的社交媒体平台上发布内容。
And at the time, I was doing it to grow
当时，我这样做是为了增加
my following. But it had this profound
我的粉丝。 但这
impact on my life. And two remarkable
对我的生活产生了深远的影响。
things happened when I did that. I
当我这样做的时候，发生了两件非同寻常的事情。 我
managed to learn faster because every
之所以能更快地学习，是因为
single day, I'm capturing what is
我每天都在记录发生在
happening to me and trying to distill it
我身上的事情，并试图将其提炼
down into something that I can share
成我可以
with the world. But more remarkably, it
与世界分享的东西。 但更令人惊讶的是，它
led me to building a following of many
让我积累了数
millions of people. And that's the basis
百万的粉丝。 这就是
that I used to launch the diary of a co.
我创办公司日记的出发点。
And that's why I want to tell you about
所以，今天我想向大家介绍一下
our sponsor today, Adobe Express. They
我们的赞助商 Adob​​e Express。
are the platform that I use to make all
我使用这个平台
the posts across my LinkedIn and across
在我的 LinkedIn 和
my Instagram. It's a couple of clicks
Instagram 上发布所有帖子。 只需点击几下鼠标，
and you don't need to be an expert. And
无需成为专家。 这
that is why I love using it because I'm
就是我喜欢使用它的原因，因为我
not an expert in graphic design. It's
并不是平面设计专家。
accessible to use for all of us, even if
即使
we don't have the technical prowess to
我们没有足够的技术能力来
design great things. So, if you want to
设计伟大的作品，它对我们所有人来说都很容易上手。 所以，如果你想和
your knowledge like I did at 24 years
我一样，在 24 岁时就开始不断扩大你的影响力和知识储备，
old, then head to adobe./stephven.
那就去 adobe./stephven 看看吧。
y/stephven
y/stephven，
and get started with Adobe Express.
开始使用 Adob​​e Express。
That's adobe.
那是Adobe。
Stephven.
斯蒂芬。
People love talking about passive
人们喜欢谈论被动
income,
收入，
&gt;&gt; especially on YouTube and the internet.
尤其是在 YouTube 和互联网上。
They everyone wants passive income. The
每个人都想要被动收入。 不用做什么事就能
idea that you can make income and do
赚钱的想法，简直
[__] all is unbelievably compelling.
太有吸引力了。   是的
&gt;&gt; Yeah.
。
&gt;&gt; Like I would like some passive income.
我想要一些被动收入。   事实
&gt;&gt; What is the reality of this? Because
真相是什么？ 因为人们真的很
there's a real obsession with figuring
痴迷于寻找
out ways to make passive income. I want
赚取被动收入的方法。 我想在
to earn money when I sleep.
睡觉的时候也能赚钱。
&gt;&gt; Um what is the reality of that? Is that
嗯，实际情况究竟如何？ 那
is that a thing? Is that possible? Is
东西存在吗？ 这可能吗？
that something I should be aiming at?
那是我应该努力的方向吗？
&gt;&gt; You should aim at that. Once you have a
你应该朝着那个方向努力。 在
million dollars in your bank account
你银行账户里拥有一百万美元
before you have a million dollars, don't
之前，千万不要
even think about passive income. You
考虑被动收入。 你
have you have no asset to actually earn
没有任何可以用来赚取
passive income off of. And your time is
被动收入的资产。 与其花时间
is through passive income and thinking
思考如何从被动收入中
how you're going to earn a percentage on
赚取一定比例的收益，不如花时间学习如何赚到你的第一个一百万美元
the principle that you've invested. If
。 如果
you make $60,000 a year, medium wage,
你在美国年收入6万美元，属于中等工资水平，那么
$60,000 a year, 8% on that isn't gonna
8%的收益率并不
get you to financial freedom. So, don't
能让你实现财务自由。 所以，别
figure out how to crack 8% to maybe I'm
想着如何把收益率从 8% 提高到
going to get 15% returns because the
15%，因为
principle is still so small. The 60,000
本金还太小。  6万这个数字
is so small. What do you have to do?
太少了。 你该怎么做？
Actually learn how do I make my income
实际上，我想学习如何才能赚到
160,000. But what's wild once people
16万美元的收入。 但一旦人们
learn how to do this and the skill of
学会了如何做到这一点，学习的技巧就像
on planet earth because you learn how to
地球上最棒的毒品一样，这真是太疯狂了。因为你学会了如何
do something and you become competent in
做某件事，并且精通
it and as soon as you get there you're
它，一旦你达到那个水平，你就会想，
like oh my gosh if that's all it took
我的天哪，如果这就是
for these people that I used to think
我以前认为很特别的那些人
were special to earn an additional
赚到额外
100,000 and now all I have to do is do
10 万美元所需要的全部，那么现在我只需要
that same process again to go from where
再次重复同样的过程，就能从
I'm at to be able to earn 1.6 6 million,
我现在的位置赚到 160 万美元，
do a 10x, sign me up. Because you get
达到 10 倍，算我一个。 因为
this confidence from learning how to do
这种自信来自于学习如何
things. And so passive income is great
做事。 因此，被动收入
at a certain stage of life and at a
在人生的某个阶段和
certain stage of financial protection,
财务保障的某个阶段固然很好，
but it is not. It is financial
但并非总是如此。 这是财务
protection. It is not for the people who
保障。 它不适合那些
are saying I want to go build something.
说“我想去建造什么东西”的人。
I want to grow something. I want to
我想种点什么。 我想
create something. It is a it is to me
创作一些东西。 对我来说，这
almost the opposite of survival
几乎是生存的反面
actually. It's your backup plan. It's
。 这是你的备用方案。 这是
your rainy day fund in case [__] hits
你的应急基金，以防万一发生什么不测
the fan. And I'm not opposed to having a
。 我并不反对制定
backup plan. It's good to have a backup
备用方案。 制定备用
plan, but 99% of your time should be
计划固然好，但你99%的时间都应该
focused on how do I make the first plan
集中在如何让第一个计划万无一失，
go freaking right and do everything I
以及
can today to control plan A.
今天尽一切可能掌控A计划上。
&gt;&gt; You talked about acquiring skills being
你之前说过，掌握技能是
the key thing there. Um obviously the
关键。 显然，
world is changing quickly because of AI
由于人工智能
and all the skills that a lot of people
以及许多人
once acquired in university you know
在大学里曾经掌握的各种技能（比如
accountants, lawyers, um podcasters I
会计师、律师、播客等等），世界正在迅速变化。
&gt;&gt; um our skills are quickly being replaced
我们的技能正在迅速被
by intelligence machines and systems
智能机器和系统所取代，
that can now do what we do. And when you
它们现在可以做我们做的事情。 当你
look around the corner at what's going
放眼
on in robotics, I think Neo, the
机器人领域，你会发现，
robotics company this week put on sale
机器人公司 Neo 本周推出了
their first humanoid robot which can
他们的第一款人形机器人，这款机器人可以
move through the physical environment
在物理环境中移动
and do things. And when I combine these
并完成各种任务。 当我将这两件事结合起来
two things, I can combine intelligence
，将智慧
with the ability to manipulate the
与操控
physical environment, I go, where are
物理环境的能力结合起来时，我就想，
where are humans going to going to be in
人类在这一切中将会处于什么位置
all this? Cuz it is conceivable. It's
？ 因为这是有可能的。 在我看来，
we employ people to do these days will
我们如今雇佣人们从事的许多工作在
be redundant in the in the near future.
不久的将来都可能变得多余，这是完全可以想象的。
&gt;&gt; Mhm. And that's not to say that there
嗯。 这并不是说不会有
won't be new jobs, but it's a difficult
新的工作机会，而是说现在很难对
time to be um investing heavily in any
任何
particular skill set. Well, some to some
特定的技能进行大量投资。 嗯，有些
skill sets because they're they're
技能确实会过时，因为它们很快
becoming invalid in no time at all. Like
就会失效。 就像我
even as a writer, so like I've written
作为一名作家一样，我已经写了
two books and I enjoy the process of
两本书，我很享受写作的过程
writing. I considered it to be one of my
。 我认为这是我的
edges. I was like, I'm quite good at
优势之一。 我当时想，我挺擅长
writing. So that's useful. You can build
写作的。 所以这很有用。 你可以打造
a personal brand. You can send good
个人品牌。 你可以写出很棒的
emails. You can convince people,
邮件。 你可以说服别人、
investors, whatever it might be. But
投资者，无论是什么人。 但
even now like [__] everyone's got like
即便现在，就像他妈的，每个人都有了
AI now chatb2. So they can just produce
AI chatb2。 所以他们可以随意炮制
AI slop and they can literally just say
人工智能垃圾，然后直接说“
write it like Steven or write it like
像史蒂文那样写”或者“像
Natalie. So the edges are are going What
娜塔莉那样写”。 所以，未来的边界正在消失。
is the edge of the future in your view?
在你看来，未来的边界是什么？
What is the edge? What is the skill I
什么是优势？ 我
should double down on that the robots
应该重点提升哪项技能，才能保证机器人
and AI aren't going to steal from me?
和人工智能不会窃取我的技能？
&gt;&gt; I think the only skill that we can
我认为
actually double down on in a world of AI
在人工智能时代，我们唯一可以着重提升的技能
is the skill of learning and adapting
就是学习和适应能力，
because we cannot predict what the world
因为我们无法预测
is going to look like in 2040. We do not
2040年的世界会是什么样子。我们不
know what robots are or aren't going to
知道机器人将来能做什么，不能做什么
be capable of. I'm not as bullish on
。 我对此并不十分看好
this. I watched Elon have a interview
。 我周末看了埃隆
over the weekend about his take on AI
关于他对人工智能的看法的采访，
and he said that it's a supersonic
他说人工智能就像一场超音速
tsunami in which he proceeded to explain
海啸，然后他解释说
that supersonic is traveling at the
超音速是指以
speed of sound and a tsunami is a wall
音速飞行，而海啸则是一堵
of water. And so if you think about that
水墙。 所以，如果你把这看作
being AI, it's coming. It's here. It's
是人工智能，那么它终将到来。 它在这里。 速度
fast. And of course, he benefits from
很快。 当然，
everybody believing all of those things
所有人都相信这些事情，他也从中获益
with all of the companies. And I am a
。 我是个
pro Elon person. I I love what he has
支持马斯克的人。 我非常喜欢他所
built. I love his mind. But I think that
取得的成就。 我喜欢他的才智。 但我认为
we're further away than people think,
我们离目标还有一段距离，虽然目标终将到来，
but it is still coming. And so the only
但它仍然会到来。 因此，
hedge that somebody can have is the
一个人唯一能拥有的保障就是
ability to adapt and learn. And what AI
适应和学习的能力。 人工智能对
should be used for with every individual
每个人来说，其真正应该发挥的作用
is the ability to learn. Acknowledge
是提升学习能力。 承认
what you don't know. That is the
自己不知道的东西。 这是
greatest strength somebody has. Really
人最大的优势。 要能够
be comfortable saying, "I do not know
坦然地说：“我不会
how to read a P&amp;L. I don't know how to
看损益表。我不会
read this legal contract. I don't know
看法律合同。我对
anything about AI and what I've heard
人工智能一窍不通，也听说过法学
LLM. Uh I don't really know what it is
硕士。呃，我真的不知道它是什么，
or agentic. What's the difference?" And
或者代理是什么。它们之间有什么区别？” 并且要能够
be able to convince yourself why that is
说服自己，为什么这是
the most important skill for you to push
你克服学习新事物障碍的最重要技能
new. that is so uncomfortable because
。 这让人很不舒服，因为这些
the the names are new and you feel like
名字都是新的，你会觉得自己像个
a freaking idiot and then you think
十足的白痴，然后你会觉得
everybody is smarter than you and that
每个人都比你聪明，而
you're just some fraud to push back on
你只是个骗子。要反驳这种想法，
that and to have some resilience through
并且要有韧性，
it to say I'm going to adapt through
告诉自己“我要适应这一切”
this. I'm going to get to the other side
。 我要努力克服困难，
and learn so that I concretely can have
学习成长，这样我才能真正有
confidence that I can change in any
信心在任何环境中都能根据
of me in that environment and I will add
环境需要做出改变，无论外部环境如何，我都能
value to that environment regardless of
为环境增添价值
whatever the external circumstances are.
。
That is the only choice. There is no
这是唯一的选择。 别无选择
&gt;&gt; Are you scared about AI?
你害怕人工智能吗？
&gt;&gt; I'm not scared at all. I'm pumped. As
我一点也不害怕。 我兴奋极了。 如
you can tell, I'm really excited because
你所见，我真的很兴奋，因为
I used to feel dumb. I used to feel like
我以前觉得自己很笨。 我以前总觉得，
there were things that these smart
这些聪明
people knew that I didn't know. And my
人知道一些我不知道的事情。
years ago when this got launched because
几年前，当人工智能问世时，我的整个人生观都发生了改变，因为它
AI has taught me in two years what I
在两年内教会了我原本需要
would have had to go to school for and
上学并获得学位才能学到的东西，而我最终
to just find out that most people who
发现，大多数
went to school for those things and had
学习这些知识并获得
degrees in them missed something
学位的人都错过了一些
critical and important. And so for me,
关键而重要的东西。 所以对我来说，
and I think people like me, and I don't
我认为像我这样的人（我不
think there's anything particularly
认为
special about who I categorize as people
我所定义的像我这样的人有什么特别之处）
like me, it is a unprecedented time to
，这是一个前所未有的时期，
that can specifically tutor you on what
可以依靠这些信息参考资料来具体指导你了解
you don't know, to actually equip you.
你不知道的东西，从而真正地为你做好准备。
you've never had this opportunity before
你以前从未有过这样的机会，
and it's not specific to you with your
而且这与你的
gender or your race or your age. It's
性别、种族或年龄无关。 它很
accessible.
容易找到。
And so I'm beyond excited because
所以我非常兴奋，因为
anything that comes up that's like, "Oh,
任何出现的情况都可能像，“哦，
this just changed the whole dynamic of
这彻底改变了整个行业的格局
the business." Guess what? I have AI to
”。 你猜怎么着？ 我拥有人工智能来
help me understand that and to help me
帮助我理解这一点，并帮助我
get whatever skill I need in this new
获得在这个新世界里所需的任何技能
world. Same thing that people 100 years
。 和100年前的人们一样
ago had to do. Same thing that 2,000
。 和2000
years ago people had to do. They just
年前的人们一样。 他们
didn't actually have a tool to help them
实际上并没有工具来帮助他们
understand what was happening to then
理解正在发生的事情，从而
learn what needed to happen from them
了解他们需要做什么，
whatever they had misunderstood Zar in
无论他们对 Zar 有什么误解，
in order to actually get to the other
以便真正掌握
side with real skills.
技能到达彼岸。
&gt;&gt; Natalie, what do you think is the most
娜塔莉，你认为
relates to what you know about who my
关于我的
audience are and what they're interested
受众群体以及他们的兴趣爱好，我们还没有谈到但应该谈到的最重要的事情是什么
in?
？
I think this is a connected subject but
我认为这是一个相关的话题，但
I would want anybody in the audience
我希望在场的每一位，
whether you make 60,000 a year a million
无论你年收入是 6 万美元、100 万美元还是 1 亿美元，都能
actually have the belief in themselves
真正相信自己
that they can learn anything that they
可以学习到任何他们
want to know and that there isn't
想知道的东西，并且
actually a barrier there that exists
实际上并不存在任何障碍。
because if I could get people to really
因为如果我能让人们真正
believe that their entire life would
相信，
change due to the access that they have
由于他们今天所拥有的资源和工具，他们的整个人生都会发生改变
today. And so taking that confidence
。 因此，有了这种自信，
that I can walk into any room with any
我可以走进任何房间，和任何
big shot with anybody who knows
大人物、任何对某个
matter that I know nothing about and
我一无所知的领域有所了解的人在一起，并且
feel totally comfortable being in that
完全适应那种
environment because you can prep
环境，因为我可以做好准备
yourself. You can learn about it and
。 你可以了解它，
life is so beautiful because you get
生活会因为你能获得
those experiences and you don't have to
这些经历而变得美好，而且你不必
be scared of them. you can learn and you
害怕它们。 你可以学习，你
can understand and there's nothing
可以理解，你没有任何问题导致
that's wrong with you to where you can't
你学不会，你也
and there's no special privilege or
没有任何特权或
special characteristics that somebody
特殊能力是别人所
has that you don't have in that you can
没有的，你可以
learn anything.
学习任何东西。
&gt;&gt; Did you used to think there were special
你以前是否认为那些处于人生顶峰的人具有
characteristics or some kind of genetic
某种特殊才能或基因
genius gene that these people at the
天赋？
change once you were in rooms with those
当你真正和这些
people? Of course, I thought that there
人待在一起后，你的想法发生了怎样的改变？ 当然，我以前认为，
clicked at birth before coming out of
在出生时，有人按下了某个天才按钮，让他们在离开
the womb where they just got to be
子宫之前就变得
special and they got to understand
特别，并且能够理解
things. I really struggled growing up
事物。 我从小就
with remembering numbers. Numbers were
记不住数字。 数字
so challenging. I would just reverse the
太难算了。 我会把
numbers and then they wouldn't stick in
数字反过来记，这样它们就不会留在
my brain and I thought I was stupid for
我的脑子里，我因此在很长一段时间里都觉得自己很笨
so much of my life. And for anybody who
。 对于任何有
also struggles with that, what you would
这种困扰的人来说，当你和
come to find out being around lots of
很多
people, successful or unsuccessful
人在一起，无论是成功人士还是不成功
people, is everybody has that thing. So
人士，你就会发现每个人都有这个问题。 所以，
the faster that you can attack it and
你越快开始学习并
get yourself comfortable with numbers,
熟悉数字，
what I realized is like that was just a
我就越意识到，那只是
story I told myself because had I ever
我给自己编造的故事，因为我曾经在
spent an afternoon on a Sunday with my
星期天的下午利用
extra time actually trying to get better
空闲时间，真正尝试提高
at remembering numbers. No, I hadn't. I
记忆数字的能力。 不，我没有。 我
just used it as an excuse. And
只是以此为借口。
successful people just limit the amount
成功人士会尽量减少
of excuses that they allow themselves to
自己
believe for why they aren't successful.
为不成功找的借口。
They take the limitation that they have
他们会正视自身的局限性，
and either they so overindex in the
要么过分强调自身的
strength and they ignore that or they
优势而忽略这一点，要么
realize that that limitation is actually
意识到这种局限性实际上已经
at a point where it is limiting them. So
限制了他们。 所以
they have to attack it and take the time
他们必须迎难而上，花时间
to get better and shore up that area to
提升自己，巩固这方面，
then be able to springboard from there.
然后才能以此为跳板。
&gt;&gt; There's also I guess another layer to
我觉得这其中还有另一层原因，
this which is men tend to rate their own
那就是即使男性和女性的实际表现相同，男性也往往会比女性更准确地评价自己的
performance higher than women do even
表现
when their actual performance is equal.
。   有
And there's a bunch of different studies
很多不同的研究都引用了这一点
that site this. There's one famous study
。 有一项著名的研究
that people always talk about which
经常被人们提及，虽然
now but it said that men apply for a job
现在可能已被推翻，但研究表明，男性在
when they meet 60% of the listed
满足职位要求的60%时就会申请工作，
qualifications while women only apply
而女性只有在
when they meet 100% of the listed
满足所有
qualifications which in part as it
要求时才会申请。这在一定程度上与
relates to top jobs um in in Europe
欧洲的高层职位有关，
people think that this is part of the
人们认为这是
reason why men are more likely to be in
男性更有可能担任
full-time top jobs um because they that
全职高层职位的部分原因，因为这种过度
overconfidence
自信
means they're more likely to apply and
意味着他们更有可能申请，
therefore more likely to um I convince
因此更有可能说服
pe other people and more likely to get
其他人，也更有可能获得
the job. So there is something there
这份工作。 所以，在
the need to feel ready and the need to
感到准备就绪和
feel qualified.
感到胜任方面，男女之间似乎存在差异。
&gt;&gt; That's so real to me.
这对我来说太真实了。
&gt;&gt; Yeah,
是的，
&gt;&gt; that is so real to me. I get to work
这对我来说太真实了。 我
with people every day and I will have a
每天都能与人共事，并且会
goal conversation with team members who
与担任相同职务的团队成员进行个人、职业和财务目标方面的对话
are in the exact same role. Let's say
。 假设
they're an account manager. One will be
他们是客户经理。 一个是
a female, one will be a male. The woman
女性，一个是男性。 这个女人就像
is like a rock star. She like the
摇滚明星一样。 她和
clients love her and she's so good and
客户一样都很喜欢她，她人也很好，而且
she just has like this little like
她身上有一种
magical spark. So, I'll be sitting with
神奇的魅力。 所以，我会和
them with their personal, professional,
她们坐下来，谈论她们的个人、职业
and financial goal conversation, and the
和财务目标，然后这位
woman will say, "Oh, I'd like to go from
女士会说：“哦，我希望我的年收入从
making $80,000 a year to maybe in a year
8 万美元增加到一年后
from now making 90,000." And the next
达到 9 万美元。” 接下来的一个
hour I will have a conversation with a
小时，我会和一个业绩
guy who is not as performant as she is,
不如她的人聊天，
and he will say, "Yeah, I'm making
他会说：“是啊，我
80,000 a year. Think in the next three
一年挣8万美元。我觉得未来
years I should be up to 200, 250." I've
三年我应该能挣到20万、25万美元。”
had this happen over and over and over.
这种情况我反复遇到过好几次。
So, I watch this in real time. And my
所以，我是实时观看的。 我通常会找个
to sit down with a girl and to say, "I
女孩坐下来，跟她说：“我
want you to imagine what [clears throat]
想让你想象一下
your life is going to look like in 3
三年后你的生活会是什么样子
years from now. So, if you're 35 years
。比如，如果你现在35
old, you're going to be 38 years old.
岁，三年后就38岁了。你的
What does life look like? Who are you
生活会是什么样子？你会和谁在一起？你能赚多少钱？
you making? Have you traveled? Do you
你旅行过吗？你
have a spouse? Do you have kids? Like
有伴侣吗？你有孩子吗？你的
what what does life look like? And what
生活会是什么样子？
I want you to do if you don't have an
如果你还没有Pinterest
account already is I want you to get
账号，我希望你
hooked up with Pinterest and you are
注册一个，
going to create a board and you just
创建一个版块，然后把
going to go through all of these
所有你真正想要的、美好的事物都列出来。
your life that you actually want. Not
不是那些你觉得‘如果我的生活能拥有这个，我的人生就会改变’之类的想法，也不是那些
you're like, if my life could include
你觉得‘如果我的生活能拥有
that, it would change my life. I would
这个，我的人生就会改变’的想法。
love to have that life. For me, that
对我来说，那
would have been full sequin suit.
会是一套亮片西装。
Because if you can't do that, you're of
因为如果你连这个都做不到，你的未来发展
course going to be stunted in what
当然会受到限制。”
you're going to do in order to get
为了达到目标，必须这样做
there. If it was a man who was
。但如果是一个男人在
struggling with that, though, I'd do the
为此挣扎，我也会做
exact same thing. That to me is the real
同样的事情。对我来说，
job of a leader is to inspire people
领导者的真正职责是激励人们，
enough not about who you are and all of
不是让他们关注你是谁以及
your accomplishments, but to actually
你所有的成就，而是让
have them see that they could have the
他们真正看到，他们可以
life that they want through the work
通过每天的工作拥有自己想要的生活
that they do every single day. and tying
。将
those two things together and being
这两件事联系起来，并在他们
ruthlessly honest with them when they do
做阻碍他们的事情时毫不留情地指出，并
things that hold them back and remove
清除他们前进
things that are in their way.
道路上的障碍。
&gt;&gt; Natalie, we have a closing tradition
娜塔莉，我们有个结束的传统，
where the last guest leaves a question
最后一位客人会给下一位客人留下一个问题，而他
for the next not knowing who they're
并不知道
leaving it for. And the question left
这个问题会留给谁。留给
for you is um a fairly well-known
你的问题其实是一个相当著名的
question actually. It is, what would you
问题。那就是：
do if you knew you would not fail?
如果你知道自己不会失败，你会做什么？
&gt;&gt; If I knew that I wasn't going to fail, I
如果我知道自己不会失败，
would just like I'd fix world hunger and
我会去解决世界饥饿问题，
I'd fix all of these things. But like
我会去解决所有这些问题。但是，如果我不去想
short of thinking that I could solve
自己能够解决
those particular problems, it's it's
这些具体问题，
selfish to not have those goals and
没有这些目标和
dreams, I just think for my actual life
梦想是很自私的，我只是在思考我自己的现实生活。
today, I really believe and preach and
今天，我真的相信并宣扬，而且发自
to my core I feel act out that
内心地觉得，
I take massive action towards goals that
我会采取大量行动去实现那些在
do seem unbelievable or unreal to me.
我看来难以置信或不切实际的目标。
And right now the the set of goals that
目前，
I have are the things that I'm very
我所设定的目标都是我非常有
confident that I'm not going to fail at.
信心不会失败的。
And I'm spending time doing those things
我正在花时间去做这些事情，让
in order to get myself as close as
自己
possible to the woman that I want to
尽可能接近我理想中的自己
become. And I could change my mind in a
。当然，一旦我实现了这些目标，我的想法可能会在
handful of months or a handful of years
几个月或几年后改变
once I've achieved those things. But I
。但我
guess I already actually do think that
认为，除了
I'm living my life short of solving
解决
world hunger and like world peace. that
世界饥饿和实现世界和平之外，我已经在努力生活了。
I'm doing everything that I know how to
我正在尽我所能去
do to make an impact on the world.
影响世界。
&gt;&gt; I noticed that um you know I've had a
我注意到，我
bunch of conversations on this show with
在这个节目中和
people like Evie Porus who is the uh the
像伊薇·波鲁斯（Evie Porus）这样的人进行过很多次对话，她是一位
the Secret Service agent and you have a
特勤局特工，你和
lot of similarities to her. I think
她有很多相似之处。我认为这部分原因在于
because of the directness in which you
你
speak and I think part of the resonance
说话的直率，而且我认为引起共鸣的部分原因
is people want to know how to be taken
是人们想知道如何
seriously in this world
在这个世界上被认真对待，
&gt;&gt; and I think they they they look at you
我认为他们…… 他们看着你，
and see someone who is like them in many
觉得你和他们在很多
ways or at least how they aspire to be
方面都很像，或者至少是他们渴望成为的样子，
but is taken seriously in a world that
而且在这个世界上，
especially as a woman in male-dominated
尤其是在男性主导的
environments especially things like the
环境中，女性很难被认真对待，尤其是在
finance industry and investment industry
金融和投资行业等领域，
it's hard to be taken seriously it's
很难被认真对待，
hard to be respected
很难被尊重。
And so people I think people have a deep
所以，我认为人们内心深处都有一种被
diminished. They are like misunderstood.
贬低的感觉，他们感觉自己不被理解，
They're not being heard. And so they
他们的声音不被倾听。因此，
when they hear someone that speaks so
当他们听到
clearly and with such conviction as you,
像你这样清晰而充满信心地表达观点的人时，他们
&gt;&gt; um they they want to learn how to do it.
就想学习如何做到这一点。
&gt;&gt; Is there anything in that regard that
在这方面，
we've we've left off? because I was I
我们还有什么遗漏的吗？因为我
was I was on your YouTube channel and I
在你的YouTube频道
was looking at some of your recent
上看了你最近的一些
videos and one of the recent videos that
视频，其中一个视频引起了很多
has been incredibly resonant to people
人的共鸣，
is this exact point which is the 1%
那就是“
secrets to make anyone respect you
让任何人瞬间尊重你的1%秘诀”
instantly.
。
&gt;&gt; Is there anything within the subject of
关于
that video and I was looking at the
这个视频的主题，我看了
comment section it was a lot of people
评论区，很多人都在
talking about how they feel
谈论他们感觉自己
someone has disrespected them or that
被别人不尊重，或者……
they feel they've been ignored or not
他们觉得自己被忽视或不被
heard. Is there anything you'd say to
倾听。你有什么想对
those people?
这些人说的吗？
&gt;&gt; Being looked down upon, being not taken
被轻视、不被
seriously is actually your superpower.
认真对待，其实是你的超能力。
And you have to convert the energy of
你必须把这种挫败感转化为动力，思考
to do in that environment next time to
下次在这种环境下该如何做才能被
be taken seriously. I went to a charity
认真对待。大约十年前，我参加了一个慈善
event was about a decade ago now and I
活动，我
remember being mortified because I was
记得当时非常尴尬，因为那正值我
in this career pivot where I was making
职业生涯的转折点，我决定
the decision to work with Brandon and
和布兰登（
&gt;&gt; your husband
你
&gt;&gt; my husband yeah and the proverbial
丈夫，我丈夫）一起工作。然后，有人问我“
question of like what do you do came
你是做什么的？”，
around to me and I fumbled the question
我支支吾吾地回答了。
and for the rest of that night and it
那天晚上，那次活动
was actually a charity trip the person
其实是慈善之旅，对方
just didn't take me seriously and they
根本没把我当回事，而我原本
were somebody that I wanted to respect
希望得到他们的尊重。
me and I was so pissed off at myself
我对自己非常生气，因为
that I messed it up that I hadn't
我搞砸了，
created something at 22 or years old
22岁的时候我竟然没能做出一些
that was more impressive that they would
更令人印象深刻的事情，让他们认真对待
take me seriously and so I made it my
我。所以，从那以后到
mission between that point and the next
第二
year when we would go on that trip for
年我们再次参加慈善之旅，我给自己定了一个目标：让他们
them to take me seriously and I had to
认真对待我。我必须
look at what do I have to do what do I
思考，我该怎么做才能让他们认真对待我。 我
have to create in order for somebody to
需要做些什么才能让别人
take a 24 year old seriously
认真对待一个24岁的年轻人？
&gt;&gt; what did you have to do and create
你又做了些什么？
&gt;&gt; well I launched a podcast and I had to
我创办了一个播客，为此我不得不
work on this communication skill cuz I
努力提升沟通技巧，因为我以前非常
was terrified to communicate. I used to
害怕与人交流。我以前根本
not be able to communicate like this. I
不会这样沟通。
had a horrifying experience when I was
我二十出头的时候有过一次可怕的经历：当时
in my early 20s where I was supposed to
我要在一个
organization. And I was nervous ahead of
机构里介绍一个新推出的领导力项目。虽然事先我很紧张，
time but was fairly confident in the
但我对
material that I was presenting. And I
自己的演讲内容相当有信心。我
walked up to the front of the room and I
走到房间前面，我
was the first person to speak. It was
是第一个发言的人。当时是
8:00 in the morning and I got through
早上八点，我讲完了五分钟，而
five minutes of my hourlong
我的
presentation. I turned around to the
演讲时长是一个小时。我转身对着
presentation screen to point out
演示屏幕指点了
something and turned back to the
一些东西，然后又转回面向
audience. And in that moment, I was
观众。就在那一刻，我
instantly petrified. The nerves took
瞬间吓坏了。紧张感席卷了
over every fiber of my body. I could not
我的全身。我无法
control what I was saying. My thoughts
控制自己说的话。我的思绪
and my words did not connect. And I
和语言完全脱节。然后，我
proceeded to give the rest of my
硬是把原本
presentation that was supposed to take
需要
an additional 55 minutes in seven. And
55分钟的演讲内容硬生生地挤出了七分钟。
then I sat at the front of the room
然后我坐在房间前面，
while everyone around me was talking
周围的人都在讨论
the things I was supposed to be
我应该重点
highlighting because I just couldn't
阐述的内容的各个方面，因为我根本无法清晰地表达出来
articulate them. And from that point for
。从那时起，
about four years, I was unable to have a
大约四年时间里，我无法
conversation with people that had a
与
larger group than four or five because
超过四五个人的群体进行对话，因为我感觉自己与人之间出现了
this disconnect for me happened and this
隔阂，
anxiousness took place and I had to work
焦虑感油然而生，我不得不努力
on this skill to learn how to
提升
communicate. And so I launched a podcast
沟通技巧。于是，我开办了一个播客，当时
and the only topic that I felt
我唯一觉得可以自在谈论的话题是商业。但
I didn't have some business expertise. I
我缺乏商业方面的专业知识。我并
wasn't naive enough to think that
没有天真地认为，在我
the wise age of 23 or 24, my early 20s,
23、24岁，也就是二十出头的时候，会有人愿意听我讲
and how to run a business. So, what did
如何经营企业。那么，
I know at that point? And what was a
我当时究竟了解什么？
problem that I was seeing? Well, I was
我看到的问题又是什么？其实，我
actually around a group of people who
身边有一群处于
were in age gap relationships and having
年龄差距较大的恋爱关系中的人，他们私下里都在讨论
all these conversations in secret, but
这些话题，但却
wouldn't publicly talk about it. And so
不愿公开谈论。所以
I started a podcast where I was talking
我开始做播客，
about what it's like being a third
谈论第三次
marriage and being a stepmom and how did
婚姻以及作为……的经历。 继母，以及
we tell our parents and what are tools
我们该如何告诉父母，还有，对于一个
somebody who is a high performer. And I
事业有成的人来说，如何应对这种令人感到无力甚至尴尬的事情。于是，我
single week. And I made it my mission
每周都坚持录制播客。那一年，我给自己定了个目标：在
that year to make a toast at every
每
single meal that made sense for me to
一顿我觉得合适的餐点上都举杯祝酒
make a toast at. So that I worked out
。这样，我就能掌握
this skill of communicating. And working
沟通的技巧。正是
out the skill of communicating is what
沟通技巧的提升，
allowed me to go from being in a room
让我从去年在那种场合
where I couldn't trust myself to even
连介绍自己的工作都不敢，到
next year and having made progress on my
第二年带着进步的自信
communication and saying, "Hey, I I know
和自信，自信地说：“嘿，我知道
that you didn't take me very seriously
你们去年没把我当回事
last year, but this year, I would never
，但今年，我以前不会这么
say it like this, but this year I've
说，但今年我
built this cool thing, and I actually
打造了一个很棒的项目，我的
have this blog that has thousands of
博客
readers every single month that is
每个月都有成千上万的读者，而且还能
generating this revenue. And you, Mr.
带来收入。” 而您，
old man might not have taken me
老先生，或许没把我的话
seriously, but I could probably help you
当回事，但我或许能帮您
in your business do the same thing
在生意上做同样的事情，
because I know that you don't know
因为我知道您
anything about this. So, I gained a
对这方面一窍不通。 因此，
skill in that process and was able to
在这个过程中我掌握了一项技能，并且能够
talk about the skill that I knew was my
谈论这项技能，我知道这是我的优势所在
angle.
。
&gt;&gt; The top comment on that video is being
那条视频下点赞最高的评论是“
nice destroyed my life.
善良毁了我的生活”。
&gt;&gt; I can understand. Of course, it did.
我能理解。 当然，确实如此。
&gt;&gt; The second comment is, "A friend to all
第二条评论是：“对所有人都是朋友，实际上就等于
is a friend to none." People really
对谁都不是朋友。” 人们
resonate with the topic of being liked
对“被人喜欢”
versus being respected. And people give
和“被人尊重”这两个话题很有共鸣。 人们
up their goals in order to be liked. And
为了博得他人的喜欢而放弃自己的目标。
they give up what they believe that they
他们放弃了自己原本认为自己
can actually accomplish. And thinking
能够实现的目标。 并且认为
themselves in order to be liked. And so
为了博得他人的喜欢而全力以赴是可以接受的。 所以
that message I know really resonated
我知道这个信息引起了
with people because I start out the
人们的共鸣，因为我在
video by talking about the difference
视频一开始就谈到了
between respect and being liked and
尊重和被喜欢之间的区别，并
really making that a choice and it's an
真正地将其视为一种选择，一种
active choice, not a passive thing that
积极的选择，而不是被动地
just happens.
发生的事情。
&gt;&gt; I wonder why that is. I wonder why so
我想知道这是为什么。 我很好奇为什么那么
many people are really focused on the
多人如此在意别人是否
the idea of being liked. They don't want
喜欢他们。 他们不想被人
to be disliked and they want to be
讨厌，又想被人
liked, but in their pursuit of being
喜欢，但在追求被人
liked, they feel like they're
喜欢的过程中，他们觉得自己
self-sabotaging in some way. like
在某种程度上是在自我破坏。 好像
they're disrespecting themselves. So
他们对自己不尊重似的。 所以
then they end up wanting to be okay with
他们最终会想要接受
not being liked.
不被人喜欢的事实。
&gt;&gt; What is the the answer there in that
在这个恶性循环中，答案究竟是什么
vicious loop?
？
&gt;&gt; You have to choose who you want to be
你必须选择你想得到谁的
liked by. And if you choose that you
喜欢。 如果你选择
respectable, you're not going to lose.
受人尊敬的人的喜爱，你就不会失败。
If you choose that you want to be liked
如果你选择讨好那些
by your co-workers because they think
认为
it's cool to [__] on the company culture
诋毁公司文化
or to
或
pretend like they're working but not
假装工作但
really care, then of course you're going
实际上漠不关心的同事，那么你当然会陷入
to get stuck in this vicious cycle
这种恶性循环，
because you actually want to be
因为你实际上想要得到
respected, but you're choosing to be
尊重，但你却选择
liked by somebody that is not
讨好那些不值得尊重的人。
I think when you find yourself in a
我认为，当你发现自己身处一个
respectable do actually like you, you
受人尊敬的人真正喜欢你的境地时，你会
start to like yourself a little bit more
开始更喜欢自己一些，
because you've made sacrifices. You have
因为你做出了牺牲。 你
to have made sacrifices in order to drop
必须做出牺牲才能舍弃过去的
the person that you were to become this
自己，成为现在的
different version of yourself. And that
自己。 这个
process is so painful because you shed
过程非常痛苦，因为你会失去
your identities and you shed people that
自己的身份，也会失去那些
you thought you needed to be dependent
你认为你需要依赖的人
upon. But as soon as you shed that and
。 但一旦你摆脱了那层束缚
you,
，
it's almost like a butterfly. You
就像蜕变成蝴蝶一样。 你会
metamorphosize into this new person, you
蜕变成一个全新的人，你
will repeat that process over and over
会一遍又一遍地重复这个过程，
again because of the confidence that it
因为它会给
brings you. And you like yourself. And
你带来自信。 而且你喜欢你自己。
when you like yourself,
当你喜欢自己时，
there's nothing better on this planet. I
这世上再也没有比这更美好的事了。 我
love my husband. I love my team members.
爱我的丈夫。 我爱我的团队成员。
I love my parents, my brother. There's
我爱我的父母和我的兄弟。
there's no amount of there's no greater
没有什么比
joy that I have than actually being my
成为
own best friend. And I don't say that
自己最好的朋友更让我感到快乐了。 我说这话并不是想说“
from like a I'm just going to hold your
我只想牵着你的
hand and we're just I'm just going to be
手，我们俩就这么定了”，而是想说“我只想
best friends with myself. I am brutally
和自己成为最好的朋友”。 我
honest with myself about what I am bad
对自己非常诚实，清楚地知道自己擅长什么
at, what I am good at. And I don't
，不擅长什么。 而且我
overindex either way. I'm just honest
两种方式都不会过度索引。 我只是
with myself because I want to like me.
对自己诚实，因为我想喜欢自己。
And when you like you because you've put
当你因为努力做自己想做的事，
in work that you have to do to not lie
不再自欺欺人地看待
to yourself about what you want, then
自己想要的东西而喜欢上自己时，
the world is opened for you to pursue
世界就会为你敞开，让你去追求
whatever opportunities because you like
任何机会，因为你喜欢
yourself and you're good with yourself
自己，你对自己很满意，
and that actually attracts more people
这实际上会吸引更多
who want to do cool [__] with you
想和你一起做酷事的人，
because most people don't like
因为大多数人都不喜欢
themselves and they're not their own
自己，他们不是自己
best friend and they think that that's
最好的朋友，他们觉得这
silly. But they are so mean to
很傻。 但他们对自己太苛刻了
themselves. And I get that cuz I used to
。 我明白，因为我以前
be so mean to myself and so critical.
对自己也很苛刻，很挑剔。
Nobody would ever say to me what I would
没有人会对我说出我会对
say to myself. I would never say to a
自己说的话。 我永远不会对
friend of mine or even my worst enemy
我的朋友，甚至是对我最痛恨的敌人说出
what I used to say to myself. And I I
我过去对自己说的话。 我
had to work on rewiring myself to
必须努力改变自己，才能
understand why I was so critical and why
明白为什么我对自己如此苛刻，为什么
I was so mean to myself to stop doing
我对自己如此刻薄，才能停止这样做，
that and to stop acting in that way that
停止那样行事，这样我才能
then allowed me to work on the things
着手解决我不喜欢自己的地方，
and fix the things that I didn't like
改正那些我不喜欢
about myself. For instance, used to
自己的地方。 例如，以前经常
watch way too much reality television. I
看太多真人秀节目。 我
hated that I watched as much reality
讨厌自己看了那么多真人秀
television as I watched, but I loved all
节目，但我又很喜欢所有《
of the Real Housewives, everything on
真正的家庭主妇》系列，
Bravo, but it made me feel crappy
Bravo 电视台的所有节目我都喜欢，但这让我感觉很糟糕，
because I liked their lives instead of
因为我喜欢她们的
liking my own lives, my own life. And
生活，而不是喜欢我自己的生活。
when you like somebody else's life and
当你喜欢别人的生活方式，却
you're living into something that you
过着自己不喜欢的生活时，
for obvious reasons. You're not creating
出于显而易见的原因，你最终会对自己非常苛刻。 你并没有创造出
the thing that you want. You're just
你想要的东西。 你只是在
circumventing. You're like shortcutting
规避问题。 你这是在走捷径
it. And that stuff to me is is just as
。 在我看来，这些东西和
of a drug as hard drugs and alcohol
毒品、酒精一样具有强大的效力，甚至可能一样有害，
because it's escapism.
因为它们能让人逃避现实。
&gt;&gt; Natalie, thank you and I'm very excited
娜塔莉，谢谢你，我非常期待将来有机会
to sit again with you in uh some point
再次和你坐下来聊聊，
in the future and get an update on your
了解一下你的
PPS.
PPS治疗进展。
&gt;&gt; I appreciate
我很想
&gt;&gt; see how you're getting on.
知道你近况如何。
&gt;&gt; Thank you.
谢谢。
&gt;&gt; Please keep doing what you're doing.
请继续保持。
&gt;&gt; Appreciate you. [music]
谢谢你。  [音乐]
Heat. Heat. N.
热浪。热。N.
[music]
[音乐]
&gt;&gt; [singing]
[歌唱]